You get a live show coming up,
你有一场表演要来了，
we'll talking that in a second.
我们稍后再讨论这个。
So quickly, for you guys in the class,
对于来到这节课的人，
homework #1 is due this Friday on the 15th,
作业一截止这周五，15 号，
project #1 is out and be due on October 1st,
项目一已经发布，截止 10 月 1 日，
even though we haven't discussed
尽管我们还没有讨论
what a Buffer Pool is yet, Buffer Pool Manager is,
什么是缓冲池，什么是缓冲池管理器，
you can get started if you want,
如果你想要开始，你可以开始，
again where you're going to allocate memory that gets it written out of disk.
在哪里分配内存，以便将其写出磁盘，
The upcoming events,
即将到来的活动，
so next, next Monday, Dana Van Aken will be giving a talk with us [] [],
下周一， Dana Van Aken 将给我们一个演讲，
giving a talk at our seminar series on the,
在我们的系列讲座上进行演讲，
talking the seminary series on Zoom on Monday,
演讲系列讲座在 Zoom 上 在星期一，
and then before that DJ2PL is having a concert this, this Saturday at 9pm
在那之前， DJ2PL 在本周六晚上 9 有一场演唱会，
on campus, in Rangos in the, in the, CUC, right.
在校园里，在 CUC 的 Rangos 。
They let you sign autographs or no?
他们是不是还让你签名？
Yeah, CMU is kind of weird,
是的， CMU 有点奇怪，
they won't let him,
他们不会让他，
like like it's a big show
这是一场盛大的演出，
and they won't let him sign autographs afterwards,
之后也不会让他签名，
some stupid yeah.
有点愚蠢，是的。
So last class is, jump right into it.
所以上一节课，跳转到那里。
So last class we were talking about alternative approaches
上一节课，我们讨论了其他方法，
to to the tuple-oriented slotted-page storage scheme, that we presented last week
对于我们上周提出的面向 tuple 的插槽页面存储方案，
and in particular we spent a lot of time talking about the log-structured storage method,
特别是我们花了很多时间讨论日志结构存储方法，
where instead of storing the actual tuples,
不是存储实际的 tuple ，
you store the log entries of of the changes you've made to tuple
而是存储对 tuple 所做更改的日志条目，
and I said that was popular in sort of modern systems that are more write intensive.
我说过这在写入密集型的现代系统中很流行。
So the three approaches we talked about,
所以，我们谈到的三种方法，
so the the tuple-oriented slotted-pages, the log-structure storage, the index-organized storage,
面向 tuple 的插槽页面，日志结构存储，索引组织存储，
these storage approaches are are ideal for workloads that are write heavy,
这些存储方法非常适合写入工作负载很重的情况，
meaning if you're doing a lot of inserts, updates or deletes, right,
这意味着如果你执行大量的插入、更新或删除，
the log-structure one is obviously better for this,
日志结构显然更适合这个，
because you're appending to the log
因为你在追加日志，
and for a lot of applications or most applications,
对于许多应用程序或大多数应用程序，
when you start off, you're going to be a more potentially write heavy workload,
当你开始时，你可能是更多写入工作负载，
but there's going to be some applications or some environments or some workloads,
但将会有一些应用程序、某些环境或一些工作负载，
where maybe you don't care about getting the best performance for writes,
你可能并不关心获得最好的写入性能，
what you really want to do is get the best performance for reads,
你真正想要做的是获得最好的读取性能，
and therefore, these approaches may not be the best way to approach it.
所以，这些方法可能不是接近它的最好方式。
So I'm going to spend a little time talking about what sort of broad categories or database applications look like,
所以，我将花一点时间讨论一下大类别或数据库应用程序是什么样子的，
and then that'll be motivation for why we want to look at an alternative storage scheme,
然后这将是我们为什么要考虑替代存储方案的动机，
where maybe we don't want to store everything just rows,
我们可能不想存储所有东西在行中，
like the tuples with all the attributes together.
tuple 将所有属性放在一起。
So this is a rough categorization,
这是一个粗略的分类，
but industry this is,
但行业是，
if you say sort of these three, these three, you say you're one of these three approaches,
如果你说这三个方法，
people roughly know what you mean.
人们大致知道你的意思。
So the first category of applications are going to call OLTP or On-Line Transaction Processing
第一类应用程序将称为 OLTP 或在线事务处理，
and these are applications where you're ingesting new data from the outside world
这些应用程序中，你可以从外部世界获取新数据，
and you're serving, you know, a lot of users at the same time,
你同时为许多用户提供服务，
so again the, the, the example application I always like to use is Amazon,
我一直喜欢使用的示例应用程序是 Amazon ，
when you go to the Amazon website,
当你去亚马逊网站，
you look, you look at products, then you click things,
你看产品，然后你点击东西，
you add them to your cart and then you purchase them,
你把它们添加到你的购物车，然后你购买它们，
maybe you go to on your account information
也许你打开你的账户信息，
and you go update, you know, your mailing address or payment information,
然后更新你的邮寄地址或付款信息，
those are all considered OLTP style workloads,
这些都被认为是 OLTP 类型工作负载，
because you're making changes to a small subset of the database,
因为你对数据库的一小部分进行更改，
like you're going updating your cart, going updating your payment information, right.
比如，你要更新你的购物车，更新你的支付信息。
So think about, you know, you know, think of like posting things on Reddit or Hacker News,
想想在 Reddit 或 Hacker News 上发布一些东西，
those are making small changes,
它们进行小的更改，
which potentially could be a large database,
这可能是一个大的数据库，
but the amount of change each query where operation is making is small,
但是每个操作进行的查询的更改量是小的，
amount of data that they're reading is small,
它们读取的很多数据是小的，
reading for a single entity.
读取单个实体。
So contrast this with On-Line Analytical Processing, OLAP workloads,
将这与在线分析处理 OLAP 工作负载进行对比，
where this is where I want to use,
这就是我想要使用，
I'm going to run queries that are going to extract or extrapolate new information across the entire data set,
我将运行将在整个数据集中提取或推断新信息的查询，
so this would be like Amazon running a query,
所以，这就像是亚马逊运行一个查询，
that says find me the number one sold product
说为我找到销售排名第一的产品，
in the state of Pennsylvania on, on a Saturday,
在宾夕法尼亚州，在星期六，
when the temperature is above 80 degrees, right,
而且当时气温超过 80 度，
It's not looking at a single person or looking at a single entity,
它不是着眼于单个人或单个实体，
but it's looking across the entire table,
而是着眼于整个表，
potentially doing a lot of JOINs also, you know, with with additional information,
可以与额外的信息做了很多 JOIN ，
similar to the things you guys have done in in homework #1.
类似于你们在家庭作业一中做过的事情。
And so in these OLAP workloads,
所以，在这些 OLAP 工作负载中，
they're going to be primarily read heavy or read only, right,
它们将主要是重读或只读，
I'm not doing single updates,
我不做单个更新，
I'm going doing large scans of and JOINs over big tables.
我要在大表上做大的扫描和 JOIN 。
And this last one is sort of, sort of a buzzword from the industry [analyst] or Gartner, called HTAP,
最后一个是行业分析师或 Gartner 的流行语，叫做 HTAP ，
and this is basically there are some applications,
这基本上就是，在某些应用程序中，
where you want to do both the OLTP style workloads and the OLAP workloads,
你可能希望同时执行 OLTP 工作负载和 OLAP 工作负载，
potentially in the same system,
可能在同一个系统中，
so instead of having to me take all my transactional data, put into a separate data warehouse
所以，不是让我把我所有的交易数据放进一个单独的数据仓库，
and then do my analytics on there,
然后在那里做我的分析，
maybe I can do some analytics directly as the data comes in,
也许我可以在数据进来的时候直接做一些分析，
we'll, we'll discuss this throughout the semester,
我们会在整个学期讨论这个问题，
but the the main two ones you want to focus on are OLTP and OLAP.
但你们要关注的主要两个是 OLTP 和 OLAP 。
Another way to think about distinction between them is,
另一种考虑它们之间区别的方法是，
sort of a simple grid like this,
这样一个简单的网格，
where along the the x axis, I'm saying whether the workload is Write-Heavy versus Read-Heavy,
在 x 轴上表示工作负载是重写入的还是重读取，
and then the y axis says how complex the queries are, right,
然后 y 轴表示查询的复杂程度，
so you can sort of divide it up like this,
所以你可以像这样划分它，
OLTP would be down in this corner,
OLTP 会在这个角落，
because we're doing potentially a lot of updates,
因为我们可能会进行大量的更新，
but the queries we're going to execute are going to be really simple,
但我们要执行的查询将非常简单，
like go SELECT single,
比如 SELECT 单个，
go SELECT * FROM the account table, where your id equals Andy,
SELECT * FROM account WHERE id = 'Andy',
it's going, getting, going, getting single things.
它会获取单个东西。
OLAP would be on the opposite end of the spectrum here,
OLAP 会在范围的另一端，
where we're doing mostly writes and the mostly reads
在这里，我们主要进行读取，
and the reads, the select queries are going to be executing are going to be,
读取， SELECT 查询将执行的，
much more complex than we do in the OLTP world,
比我们在 OLTP 的世界做的 要复杂得多，
think it Q9 Q10 in homework #1.
想想作业一中的 Q9 Q10 。
So OLAP, the OLDP term goes back to the 80s,
所以， OLTP 术语可以追溯到 80 年代，
OLAP comes from the 90s,
OLAP 诞生于 90 年代，
this guy that named Jim Gray was famous database researcher,
这个叫 Jim Gray 的人是著名的数据库研究员，
who invented a lot of stuff, when we talk about this semester,
他发明了很多东西。当我们谈到这个学期时，
he wrote an article saying,
他写了一篇文章说，
hey, there's this new category of workloads in the early 90s called OLAP
90 年代初出现了一种新的工作负载类别，称为 OLAP ，
and we should pay attention to it,
我们应该注意它，
turns out he was actually getting paid by a company
事实证明，他从一家公司获得报酬，
who was trying to sell a OLAP database system product in the early 90s
这家公司在 90 年代初试图销售一种 OLAP 数据库系统产品，
and the paper got retracted, but the name still stuck around,
论文被撤回，但这个名字仍然存在，
and then Jim Gray won the Turing Award in databases in, I think 96,
然后 Jim Gray 在 96 年获得了关于数据库的图灵奖，
a very famous data researcher,
他是一位非常著名的数据研究员，
has anyone heard the story, you know,
有人听说过这个故事吗，
has anyone heard of Jim Gray before,
之前有人听说过 Jim Gray 吗，
one, sort of guy,
一个，一个人，
so he famously got lost at sea in the San Francisco Bay in 2006,
他于 2006 年在旧金山湾的海上失踪是出了名的，
he was out sailing by himself,
他独自一人出海航行，
it was not a joke,
这不是一个玩笑，
he was out sailing by himself and his boat disappeared,
他独自出海航行，他的船不见了，
and it's actually one of the early examples of [] searching,
这是早期的[]搜寻的例子之一，
because they actually moved satellites to take pictures of the San Francisco Bay
因为他们移动了卫星来拍摄旧金山湾的照片，
and try to, you know, people look at the images, try to find the, the boat,
人们查看图像，试图找到那艘船，
and they never found him,
但他们一直没找到他，
all right, so that's a weird, but,
好的，这太奇怪了，
I never met him, but a lot of,
我从来没见过他，但是很多，
we talked about like, you know, going to Pluto versus reading, you know, reading the book in front of you,
我们谈到的去冥王星，在你面前读书，
you know, that was a Jim Gray metaphor,
这是 Jim Gray 的比喻，
he had a lot of interesting things like that.
他有很多这样的有趣的事情。
So HTAP would be sort of the middle,
所以 HTAP 应该在中间，
so, so today I want to spend time talking about,
所以，今天我想花点时间谈谈，
why the things we talked about so far in the the previous two lectures,
为什么到目前为止，我们在前两节课中谈到的东西，
they're gonna be good for for OLTP and not OLAP
它们将有利于 OLTP 而不是 OLAP ，
and then we'll design a, a storage scheme, that is better for OLAP.
然后我们将设计一个更适合 OLAP 的存储方案。
So to do this,
为了做到这一点，
we're going to do a real simple example, using a real database.
我们将使用一个真实的数据库来做一个非常简单的示例，
so this is, this is roughly what the Wikipedia database looks like,
所以这大概就是维基百科数据库的样子，
it runs a software called MediaWiki,
它运行着一个名为 MediaWiki 的软件，
it runs off of MySQL and PHP,
它运行在 MySQL 和 PHP 上，
it's open source, you can go look at it
它是开源的，你可以去看看它，
and the, the, the schema roughly looks like this, right,
[模式]大概是这样的，
there'll be useracct, people that are actually making changes,
有 useracct ，那些进行修改的人，
there'll be pages, like the articles in Wikipedia,
有 pages ，就像维基百科上的文章，
and then there'll be revisions for those articles,
然后有 revisions ，对于那些文章，
and so there's a foreign key reference for a revision,
这里 revision 有一个外键引用，
you have the user that created the change
你有创建更改的用户，
and then an ID to the actual page itself,
然后是页面本身的 ID ，
but all the text itself is going to go in the revision part,
但所有的文本本身都将在 revision 部分，
and there's, there's a, there's a foreign key going back from page to revision,
这里有一个外键从 page 回到 revision ，
so, so you can find the latest revision.
所以，你可以找到最新的版本。
So I said this before, I say it again,
我在之前已经说过了，
the relational model does not define or specify that,
关系模型并没有定义或指定，
anything about how we should store the data in a table, right,
关于我们应该如何将数据存储在表中，
so in all the examples I've shown so far,
所以在我目前为止展示的所有例子中，
we're just showing the tuple,
我们只是展示 tuple ，
every tuple, all the attributes one after another,
每个 tuple ，所有一个接一个的属性，
yes, we said there was overflow pages for large attributes,
是的，我们说过大型属性有溢出页面，
but you know that in general all all the smaller attributes store together,
但是，通常所有较小的属性都存储在一起，
but there's nothing about, again, the relational model says you have to do that,
但是，关系模型并没有说你必须这样做，
just sort of what we as humans came up with first,
只是我们作为人类最先想到的东西，
it's easy for us to conceptually think about.
我们很容易从概念上思考。
But again, for OLAP workloads,
但是，对于 OLAP 工作负载而言，
this may not be the best thing.
这可能不是最好的选择。
So let's see how it works for OLTP, right,
那么让我们来看看它是如何为 OLTP 工作的，
again for OLTP, it's going to be a bunch of small queries,
对于 OLTP ，它将是一堆小查询，
that are going, it's going to be a lot of queries that are going to be really simple
这将是非常简单的大量查询，
and they're going to read or write a small amount of data
它们将读取或写入少量数据，
relative to all the data in the database right.
相对于数据库中的所有数据。
So the first query here is just going get the,
这里的第一个查询将是获取，
for a given page, given its pageID,
对于给定页面，给出它的 pageID ，
go get me the latest revision for it,
为我获取它的最新版本，
so to JOIN against the revision table,
所以，对 revision 表做 JOIN ，
but it's one page and one revision,
但它只有一页和一个版本，
it's retrieving that.
它获取的。
The next one is the UPDATE query,
下一个是更新查询，
is somebody login,
有人在登录吗，
you have a userID, assuming they've been authenticated
你有一个 userID ，假设他们已经过身份验证，
and you update the user account,
你更新用户账户，
with the timestamp at the last time they login
使用他们最后一次登录的时间戳，
and the hostname from where they login from.
和他们登录的主机名。
Or if I do an INSERT into the revision table,
或者，如果我在 revision 表中执行 INSERT ，
it's, it's inserting a single row, right.
它会插入一行。
And this is what usually people end up with,
这通常是人们得到的结果，
when they build a brand new application,
当他们在构建一个全新的应用程序时，
like if you're, if you're, you know, if you're going to create a startup
比如，如果你要创建一家初创公司，
and you start building some online service,
你开始构建一些在线服务，
you usually end up with something that looks like this,
你通常会得到这样的结果，
because you don't have any data in the beginning,
因为你一开始没有任何数据，
you need to get it
你需要得到它，
and you make a website
你做了一个网站，
and then your website is going to run these kind of queries.
然后你的网站会运行这些查询。
And for OLAP, we're going to do more complicated things,
而对于 OLAP ，我们将做更复杂的事情，
that require us to look at larger portions of the table,
需要我们查看表的更大部分，
so this is actually a rough approximation of a real query,
这是真实查询的粗略近似值，
where people were running,
当人们运行，
you, you would look at the user accounts in Wikipedia
你看一下维基百科的用户账号，
and you find all the, the login attempts from, from users
你会发现所有来自用户的登录尝试，
that had an IP address or a hostname that ended with .gov, right,
有 IP 地址或主机名以 .gov 结尾，
because it was like a, there was a scandal late 2000s, early 2010s,
因为，有一起丑闻发生在 2000 年代末，2010 年代初，
where like people in congress were having their staff go update Wikipedia
国会里的人让他们的工作人员更新维基百科，
to say more flattering things about the congressman or congresswoman
对国会议员或国会女议员说更多恭维的话，
like Pence did this, Joe Biden did this, right,
比如 Pence 做了这个， Joe Biden 做了这个，
so this query could find all people that were doing that,
所以，这个查询可以找到执行这个操作的所有人，
so basically were paying government employees to go update Wikipedia,
所以，基本上是付钱让政府雇员更新维基百科，
and they shouldn't have.
他们不应该这么做。
Again, so this is queries we're going to execute on data
这个我们要在数据上执行的查询，
after we've already collected it from, from sort of the OLTP portion of the application.
在应用程序的 OLTP 部分收集数据后。
So the thing we need to talk about now is,
所以我们现在要谈的是，
what I'll call the, the, the storage model,
我所说的存储模型，
and this is going to be,
这将是，
how the database system is going to physically organize tuples in, in disk and in memory
数据库系统如何在物理上组织 tuple 在磁盘和内存中，
relative to their other tuples in their own attributes.
相对于它们各自的属性中的其他 tuple 。
And so up until now,
到目前为止，
again, I've been assuming that all of the attributes are contiguous for a tuple
我假设所有的属性对于 tuple 来说都是连续的，
and that's sort of roughly called a row store,
这叫做行存储，
but again, for OLAP, that actually may not be the best thing,
但是，对于 OLAP ，这可能不是最好的事情，
and we'll see why in a second.
我们很快就会知道为什么。
And the reason why we have to discuss this part of a system,
我们之所以要讨论系统的这一部分，
because there is a clear distinction in the marketplace now in, in, in, in the database world
因为在数据库世界现在的市场中，存在明显的区别，
between a row store system and a column store system,
在行存储系统和列存储系统之间，
like a row store system, you'd want to use that for OLTP
对于行存储系统，你想要将其用于 OLTP ，
and for a column store system, you'd want to use that for OLAP.
对于列存储系统，你想要将其用于 OLAP ，
And if anybody tries to say,
如果有人试图说，
hey, I have a fast row store that you can use for analytics,
嘿，我有一个快速的行存储，你可以用来进行分析，
you know, you should be very skeptical.
你应该非常怀疑。
All right, so the three choices to do are
好的，三个选择是，
the the N-ary Storage Model or NSM, that's the row store,
N-ary 存储模型或 NSM ，这是行存储，
Decomposition Storage Model, DSM, that's the column store
分解存储模型， DSM ，这是列存储，
and then a hybrid approach is actually, this is the most common one for column stores,
然后是混合方法，这是列存储最常见的方法，
well, we'll see why in a second,
我们一会儿就会知道原因，
it's called PAX or partition attribute across,
它被称为 PAX 或分区属性访问，
and most time people say they have a column store,
大多数时候，人们说他们有一个列存储，
they really have the PAX one,
他们有的是 PAX ，
but it's, it's a, it's, it's, it's not a major, major, major difference.
但这不是很大的区别。
Let's start with the first one, the NSM row store,
让我们从第一个开始， NSM 行存储，
again, this is what we've already said so far this semester,
这是我们本学期到目前为止已经说过的内容，
we assume that almost all the attributes for a given tuple
我们假设给定 tuple 的几乎所有属性
are going to be stored continuously in a single page,
都连续存储在一个页面中，
you know, one after another,
一个接一个，
and the idea is,
我们的想法是，
again, you're going across in the page
你要在页面上，
and you're laying out all the the data for a given tuple
放置给定 tuple 的所有数据，
and you don't start anything,
你不会开始任何东西，
you don't, you don't lay down any bits for the next tuple
你不会为下一个 tuple 放下任何比特，
until you finish the the current tuple.
直到你完成当前的 tuple 。
And the reason why this is going to be better for an OLTP system,
这对于 OLTP 系统来说会更好的原因，
as I already said before,
正如我之前已经说过的，
OLTP application is that,
OLTP 应用程序是，
most of the queries are going to be accessing a single entry or single tuple, right,
大多数查询将访问单个条目或单个 tuple ，
and so now I can go to a single page
现在，我可以转到一个页面，
and get all the data I need for that single attribute,
获取单一属性所需的所有数据，
and that's really all I need to satisfy that query.
这就是我满足该查询所需的全部数据。
We already talk about page sizes,
我们已经谈到了页面大小，
but again, it's always been some multiple of hardware pages.
但是，它总是硬件页面的倍数。
So this is basically the same layout that we saw before, right,
所以这基本上是我们之前看到的相同的布局，
that we have some database page,
我们有一些数据库页面，
we have a header in the front, with the slot, slot array,
我们在前面有一个 header ，接着 slot array ，
and then as we start scanning through our table and want to start or scanning through,
然后，当我们开始扫描我们的表，
the application, which starts inserting data,
开始插入数据的应用程序，
it's just going to go append the entries to the end
它只会将条目追加到末尾，
and keep adding, adding more and more
并不断添加越来越多，
and then think it filled up, right,
然后认为它已经填满了，
and again, now if any query comes along,
现在，如果出现任何查询，
says you SELECT * FROM this table, where id equals something,
比如 SELECT * FROM 从这个表中， id 等于某个东西，
we could go to get this one page,
我们可以获取这一页，
jump to the offset as defined in the slot array,
跳到 slot array 中定义的偏移量，
and we get all the data that we need.
我们就可以获得所需的所有数据。
So let's see now how this works in our Wikipedia example,
让我们看看这在我们的维基百科示例是如何工作的，
say you have a query here,
假设你在这里有一个查询，
where someone wants a login,
其中有人想要登录，
they're passing a username and a password,
他们传入用户名和密码，
we're just checking to see whether that matches,
我们检查一下是否匹配，
this is roughly how you log into a database back application,
这大致就是登录到基于数据库应用程序的方式，
using,
使用，
if you do authentication database, it roughly looks like this.
如果你对数据库进行身份验证，它大致就是这样。
Again, so we can ignore how we actually find the data that we want for one given user,
我们可以忽略如何为一个给定的用户找到我们想要的数据，
but assume there's some kind of index,
但假设有某种索引，
hash table, B+ tree, it doesn't matter,
哈希表，还是 B+ 树，并不重要，
we'll cover that in lecture 8,
我们将在第 8 课中讨论这个，
but there's a way to say,
但有一种方法可以说明，
for this, for this user account, here's the record ID and offset.
对于这个用户帐户，这是记录 ID 和偏移量。
So now we go into our page directory
现在，我们进入页面目录，
and we find the page that has the data we're looking for,
找到包含我们要查找的数据的页面，
we look in the slot array,
我们查看 slot array ，
we jump to some offset,
跳到某个偏移量，
and now we have all the data that we need for this query, query
现在我们有了查询所需的所有数据，
and we can produce the result.
我们可以生成结果。
Again, so this is ideal for OLTP,
这是 OLTP 的理想选择，
because all the data is contiguous.
因为所有数据都是连续的。
Same thing, we want to do an insert,
同样的事情，我们想要做插入，
all we need to do is look at page directory,
我们所需要做的就是查看页面目录，
find a page that has a free slot,
找到一个有空闲空间的页面，
go bring it a memory, assume it's this one,
给它一个内存，假设就是这个，
and then, you know, append it to the end of it, right.
然后，把它追加到末尾。
That's fine.
那很好。
But now if I try to run that query,
但是现在，如果我尝试运行这个查询，
before again where I'm trying to find all the,
其中我想找到所有，
get the number of times people have logged in per month,
获得人们每月登录的次数，
if they end with a hostname with .gov,
如果它们的主机名以 .gov 结尾，
now, you see, in this case here,
现在，在本例中你可以看到，
I got to scan all the pages in the table,
我必须扫描表中的所有页面，
because I need to look at everything, all the user accounts,
因为我需要查看所有内容，所有用户帐户，
and then when I bring a page in,
然后当我带入一个页面，
the, the way, we're going to roughly execute the query,
我们将粗略地执行查询的方式，
we haven't got through how to do query execution yet,
我们还没有了解如何执行查询，
but the roughly the idea is that,
但大致的想法是，
we got this WHERE clause thing, that's look up on hostname,
我们有这个 WHERE 子句，这是关于主机名的，
we, we need to go find the tuples in a page,
我们需要在一个页面中找到 tuple ，
that where that that predicate on the hostname is satisfied.
主机名上的谓词是满足的。
So the only data we really need to look at is just the hostname here,
所以，我们真正需要查看的唯一数据就是这里的 hostname ，
then we've got to do the, the aggregate on the lastLogin, for the GROUP BY,
然后我们必须对 lastLogin 进行聚合，对于 GROUP BY ，
and so that means the only data we really need to look at
这意味着我们需要查看的唯一数据，
for that portion of the query is just these attributes here.
对于那个查询部分来说，就是这些属性。
So what's the obvious problem?
那么最明显的问题是什么？
You have to go through all the rows
你必须遍历所有的行，
and you brought a bunch of data and you actually don't need,
你带来了一堆数据，而你实际上并不需要，
so in order to get just the attributes I needed,
所以，为了获得我需要的属性，
I had to bring in the entire page,
我必须引入整个页面，
but the entire page brings on a bunch of attributes,
但是整个页面带来了一些我不需要的属性，
userID, userName, userPass that I don't need for this query,
userID, userName, userPass ，我在这个查询中不需要的，
so I'm basically doing useless IO,
所以我在做无用的 IO ，
I'm fetching data in from disk
我从磁盘中获取数据，
and I don't even need it at all, right,
但我根本不需要它，
so not only is that slow,
这不仅很慢，
but in some systems you pay per disk IOPS,
而且在某些系统中，你为每个磁盘 IOPS 付费，
in Aurora on Amazon, you pay,
在亚马逊的 Aurora 上，你付费，
if you read something from disk,
如果你从磁盘上读取某些东西，
you pay per the number of IO operations you're doing for a query, right,
你按查询的 IO 操作次数付费，
so in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
I be paying for data that I, that I don't actually even need.
我是在为我实际上并不需要的数据付费。
So that's the obvious problem with NSM,
这就是 NSM 的明显问题所在，
again, great for inserts, updates, deletes,
它非常适用于插入、更新和删除，
great for queries that need to get the entire, all the data for a for a single entity in the database,
也适用于需要获取数据库中单个实体的全部数据的查询，
but if you want to scan large portions of of a table
但是，如果你想要扫描表的大部分，
and you only need a subset of the attributes,
并且只需要一个子集的属性，
which most OLAP queries only need, right,
大多数 OLAP 查询所需要的，
it's very rare what you call a SELECT * on a and a really wide, huge table,
在一个很大的表上调用 SELECT * 是非常罕见的，
because you're basically dumping the whole thing out,
因为你基本上是在获取整个东西，
there's utilities to make that go faster other than SELECT *.
还有其他实用程序可以让它运行得更快，除了 SELECT * 。
So this can be bad for OLAP,
所以，这可能对 OLAP 不利，
because we're bringing in data that we don't need.
因为我们带来了不需要的数据。
The this is sort of low level detail,
这是一种低级别的详细信息，
but going back to this portion here,
但回到这里的这一部分，
like if you think about how you would actually execute the query to do this, to, run this predicate,
考虑如何执行查询，运行这个谓词，
I'm jumping around to different locations in in memory
我跳转到内存中的不同位置，
to to do my scan, right,
以执行我的扫描，
so like I gotta read this header for the first tuple,
我必须读取第一个 tuple 的 header ，
figure out where you know how far I need to jump over to get the hostname,
找出我需要跳过多远才能获得 hostname ，
then I can maybe look at the lastLogin,
然后我也许可以查看 lastLogin ，
I'm computing aggregate as I go along,
我一直在计算聚合，
but then I jump down to the next tuple
但我跳到下一个 tuple ，
and then jump over that to get get to the, you know to its hostname attribute.
然后跳过，以获得它的 hostname 属性。
So in a modern super scale of CPU,
在现代超大规模的 CPU 中，
this is terrible,
这是很糟糕的，
because there's a bunch of these non-sequential operations,
因为有一堆这样的非顺序操作，
that could also became non-deterministic,
也可能变得不确定，
where, I, my memory locations that I'm accessing is, is going to be,
我访问的内存位置是，
it's not random,
它不是随机的，
because you're always going in in increasing order,
因为你总是以递增的顺序进入，
but it's not going to be like I'm just reading strides of memory
但这不会像我只是读取[步长的]内存，
and and crunching through it very quickly.
并非常快地处理它。
It's a low level of detail,
这是一个低层次的细节，
that we don't really cover in the semester,
我们在本学期没有真正涉及到，
but it's, it's at least worth discussing.
但它至少值得讨论。
And then we'll see this,
然后我们会看到这个，
we'll cover compression later in in this lecture,
我们将在这节课的后面部分讨论压缩，
but in this case here,
但在这里，
we're not going to be able to get, you know, good compression rate,
我们将无法获得良好的压缩率，
if you want to reduce the amount of or pack in more data within a single page,
如果你想要减少单个页面中的数据量或在单个页面中填充更多数据，
because all the attributes for a given table are just thrown together in that page,
因为给定表的所有属性都被放在该页面中，
and there's no, there's going to be less chance for repeatability
重复性的机会会更少，
or less chance for identifying,
识别的机会也会更少，
hey, these these values are the same,
嘿，这些值是一样的，
I can compress them really well, right,
我可以把它们压缩得很好，
again, is going back,
回来这里，
we have, we have a userID, that's going to be integer,
我们有 userID ，是一个整数，
userName is going to be random string,
userName 是随机字符串，
userPass random string,
userPass 是随机字符串，
it's going to be all different value domains
这将是所有不同的值域，
and that's not going to be ideal for compression.
这对于压缩来说并不是理想的。
So the alternative approach is the DSM, the column store, decomposition storage model,
另一种方法是 DSM ，列存，分解存储模型，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
instead of storing all the attributes for a single tuple together in a page,
不是在一个页面中存储单个 tuple 的所有属性，
we're going to store all the attributes for all tuples,
我们将存储所有 tuple 的所有属性，
sorry, for all tuple, to store a single attribute in a single page, right.
抱歉，对于所有 tuple ，在一个页面中存储单个属性。
I've just had that lastLogin field,
我有 lastLogin 字段，
instead of having all intermix with the other attributes within a single page,
不是将所有属性与单个页面中其他属性混合在一起，
I only just have that login lastLogin attribute.
我只有 lastLogin 属性。
And this is going to be ideal now for OLAP queries,
这对于 OLAP 查询来说将是理想的，
because they're going to scan the entire table
因为它们将扫描整个表，
and only for, only a subset of the attributes,
只扫描属性的一部分，
and now when I go fetch a page from disk,
现在，当我从磁盘获取页面时，
I'm only getting data,
我只获取数据，
I know I'm only getting data from the attributes that I actually need,
我知道我只获取实际需要的属性的数据，
and not for other things that just sort of gets carried along for the ride.
而不是其他[顺带]的东西。
So the,
所以，
again, the benefit of a declared language like SQL is that,
像 SQL 这样的声明语言的好处是，
you don't have to know, not to care,
你不必知道，不必关心，
whether you're running on a row store system versus a column store system,
自己是在行存储系统上运行，还是在列存储系统上运行，
your same SQL query works just fine, just the same,
你相同的 SQL 查询，可以很好地工作，（结果）是一样的，
but now it's the database system responsibility,
但现在这是数据库系统的责任，
meaning us people actually building it,
意味着我们实际构建它的人，
it's, it's our responsibility
这是我们的责任，
to be to take data, split it up into separate columns, separate attributes,
获取数据，将其拆分成单独的列，分隔属性，
and then stitch it back together to when we need to produce results.
然后在需要产生结果时将其缝合在一起。
All right, so this is just another the same diagram I shared before,
好的，这只是我之前分享的另一个相同的图表，
again, the way to think about this is that,
同样，考虑这一点的方法是，
for the first column here, first attribute column A,
对于这里的第一列，第一个属性列 A ，
we have a separate file with a bunch of pages,
我们有一个单独的文件，其中有一系列页面，
it'll have a header, now,
现在，它会有一个 header ，
just, you know, tell us what, what's in, what's inside the page,
告诉我们页面里面有什么，
and then now we'll have this, the null bitmap,
然后我们就有了这个 null bitmap ，
for all the columns, sorry, for all the values within that within this column,
对于所有列，抱歉，是该列中的所有值，
followed by now the contiguous values for all the tuples in the table,
接下来是表中所有 tuple 的连续值，
and we just do it for the next one and the next one.
我们在下一个和下一个也是这样做的。
All right, and so these are still,
好的，所以这些仍然是，
these files will still be broken up as as database pages like we talked about before,
这些文件仍然会像我们之前谈到的那样被分解成数据库页，
so either four kilobytes, eight kilobytes, whatever, whatever the system supports,
无论是 4 千字节还是 8 千字节，无论系统支持什么，
but the, the file itself will contain, again, just just the data for a single attribute
但是，文件本身将包含，仅仅是单个属性的数据，
and now the metadata overhead for these different files
现在这些不同文件的元数据开销
is actually much less than a in a row store,
实际上比行存储中的要少得多，
because I don't have to keep track of like all additional,
因为我不必像跟踪所有其他的，
like every single, every single column, whether it could be null or not,
比如每一列，它是否为空，
the, the different information about the offsets or where to find things, right,
关于偏移量或在哪里找到东西的不同信息，
these are all going to be the metadata at the store,
这些都将是存储中的元数据，
because it's just all the same value domains or all the same attribute type,
因为它们都是相同的值域，相同的属性类型，
it's being much less than than a row store.
它比行存储小得多。
All right, so, the idea here again,
好的，所以，这里的想法是，
so we go back to our Wikipedia example,
所以我们回到维基百科的例子，
we just take every column for our table
我们只获取表中的每一列，
and then we're going to store that as a separate page, right,
然后将其存储为单独的页面，
so if you go back to the hostname example,
如果你回到主机名的示例，
within a single page, again, we're only storing values for the hostname column,
在单个页面中，我们只存储主机名列的值，
and we'll have separate pages for all our attributes.
我们的所有属性都将有单独的页面。
So now if we go back to this, the OLAP query here,
所以，如果我们回到这里的 OLAP 查询，
then we're doing the lookup the counting number of logins per month, with for the government addresses,
然后我们进行查找，政府地址每月登录的数量，
the first part executing the query is going get the hostname,
执行查询的第一部分是获得 hostname ，
well, that's assuming it's one page per attribute,
好的，这是假设每个属性都有一个页面，
that's going fetching that one page
它将获取单个页面，
and then doing the scan, just ripping through the column
然后执行扫描，只需遍历列，
and identifying all the matches for that for that hostname.
并识别与该 hostname 匹配的所有内容。
And again, I have complete utilization of all the data that I brought in,
我已经完全利用了我引入的所有数据，
because I'm only bringing in the data I need for for this query,
因为我只引入了这个查询所需的数据，
I'm not bringing attributes that I don't care about.
我不会引入我不关心的属性。
And then now we'll talk about this later,
然后我们将在后面讨论这个，
how we do,
我们如何做，
we talk about query execution, how we match things up,
我们讨论查询执行，如何进行匹配，
but assuming I keep track of a list of,
但是假设我跟踪一个列表，
here's the offsets of the tuples within this column that match my predicate.
这是该列中与我的谓词匹配的 tuple 的偏移量。
Then I go to now to the lastLogin page,
然后我现在转到 lastLogin 页面，
go fetch that, and again, that only has data that we need,
去取那个只有我们需要的数据，
and then now I know how to jump to the different offsets of the matching hostnames
然后，现在我知道如何跳到匹配 hostname 的不同偏移量，
to find the right offset for the login, the login timestamp,
以找到正确的 login 偏移量，即登录时间戳，
and then compute whatever I need for the query.
然后计算出查询所需的内容。
This is clear?
这里清楚了吗？
Who here has heard a column store before today?
今天在座的各位，有谁之前听说列存储？
Less than 10%, okay.
少于 10% ，好的。
Again, so this is a,
所以，这是一种，
it sort of seems obvious now,
这似乎是显而易见的，
that this is clearly the way you want to do this,
这显然是你想要做的方式，
but, before up to 15 years ago, 20 years ago,
但是，在 15 年前，在 20 年前，
this is not how any database system was actually built,
任何数据库系统都不是这样构建的，
it was very, very rare.
这是非常罕见的。
Sorry, your question is,
抱歉，你的问题是，
if I go back to the row store example,
如果我回到行存储的例子，
this one here,
这里的这个，
your question is, what,
你的问题是，
if even in this one, do I have to.
即使在这里，我是否也必须。
Oh, like, this one,
哦，比如，这个，
literally, okay, yes, why.
从字面上看，是的，为什么。
Oh, okay. The question is,
哦，好的，问题是，
I said there's some index,
我说过有一些索引，
I didn't say what it was,
我没说那是什么，
there's some magic way to say,
有一种神奇的方式可以说，
look at the WHERE clause,
看看 WHERE 子句，
where it says userName equals something,
它说 userName 等于某个东西，
because you would go to index on userName
因为你会走到 userName 的索引，
and I magically got to the single record,
而我神奇地得到了单一的记录，
again, the record ID, page ID and offset,
record ID ， page ID 和偏移量，
how do I do that,
我怎么做的，
that's what the index does,
这就是索引的作用，
that's next week, right,
那是下个星期，
it's just a key value,
这只是一个键值，
you think about a key value map or associate array,
你可以想象成键值映射或关联数组，
for given key, the userName, give be the record ID or record IDs if it's non unique, that matched this,
对于给出的 userName ，给出匹配的 record ID 或 record IDs（如果不是唯一的），
then then so I get that my index gives me the record ID,
我的索引给我 record ID ，
I look at my page directory,
我查看我的页面目录，
said okay, I need page one, two, three,
说，好的，我需要页面 1 2 3 ，
where's that,
它在哪里，
it's on here on, it's either in memory or on disk,
它要么在内存中，要么在磁盘上，
I go get it
我去拿它，
and now I have the slot number from the record ID
现在我有了 record ID 中的插槽编号，
and I look in that page and jump to that slot,
我查看那个页面，并跳到那个插槽，
get what I need,
获得我需要的东西，
so that allows me to jump exactly to the page I need
所以，这使我可以准确地跳到我需要的页面，
and then within that page go to get exactly the record I need,
然后在该页面中找到我需要的记录，
but again, like I only need one,
但是同样，如果我只需要一个，
assuming userNames are unique,
假设 userName 是唯一的，
I only need one userName,
我只需要一个 userName ，
but I had to go fetch all these other rows I don't actually need.
但我不得不去取，我实际上并不需要的所有其他行。
Yes.
是的。
What do you mean, slightly more implementation?
你说的是什么意思，稍微更多地实现？
I would say they are equally as hard,
我想说它们是一样难的，
if you don't care about other bunch other protections,
如果你不关心其他一堆保护措施，
we're not talking about transactions,
我们不是在讨论事务，
but, if you don't care about those things,
但是，如果你不关心这些事情，
then yeah, I would agree that a row store would be easier to implement,
那么，是的，我同意行存储将更容易实现，
again, you just like everything's here, I assume it all packs in, then yeah,
所有东西都在一起，那么是的，
then, assuming that every record can fit into a single page, ignoring overflows,
假设每条记录都可以放在一个页面中，忽略溢出，
then a row store would be potentially easier, yes.
那么行存储可能会更容易，是的。
Yes.
是的。
So his question is,
所以，他的问题是，
is the fact, that the database system store is a row store versus a column store,
数据库系统存储是行存储还是列存储，
is this something that's configurable by table
这是可以对表配置的东西，
or is this it sort of all or nothing?
还是一种全有或全无？
Most systems are going to be row only or column only,
大多数系统将只使用行或列，
the, the HTAP stuff, the hybrid stuff that sort of tries to do sort of both,
HTAP 的东西，混合的东西，试图同时做到这两种，
the, so typically you would say,
所以通常你会说，
yeah, so in most systems you would say,
是的，所以在大多数系统中你会说，
I know I'm using the system, it's going to be a column store,
我知道我在用这个系统，它将是一个列存储，
so I'll store everything in there,
所以我将在那里存储所有内容，
the tables will be column,
表将成为列，
now, even though I said, like the,
尽管我说过。
like even though it's a, it's a column store
尽管它是一个列存储，
and we're going to be optimized for for readonly queries,
我们将针对只读查询进行优化，
people obviously want to update data, right,
人们显然想要更新数据，
and so the way you typically get around that is,
所以，通常的解决方法是，
these systems would have a, a sort of row store buffer area,
这些系统会有一种行存储缓冲区，
and it typically log-structured,
它通常是日志结构的，
where if I have any updates,
如果我有任何更新，
I apply them to that row portion
我会将它们应用到行部分，
and then periodically I would then merge them into the column store,
然后定期将它们合并到列存储中，
that's one approach to this,
这是解决这一问题的一种方法，
Oracle does a different approach,
Oracle 采用了一种不同的方法，
where the row store is considered the primary storage location of the database,
其中行存储被视为数据库的主存储位置，
but then they'll make a copy of of your tables in a column store format
但随后他们将以列存储格式制作表的副本，
and they they're responsible for keeping the sort of things updated for you,
并负责为你保持更新，
so different approach, these different things,
所以不同的方法，不同的东西，
but typically if the system supports I want row store versus a column store,
但通常如果系统支持我想用行存储而不是列存储，
you, you could define it on a per table basis,
你可以在每张表的基础上定义它，
but most systems don't do that.
但大多数系统不这样做。
Yes.
是的。
This question is,
这个问题是，
if I have as many discs as I have columns,
如果我有和列一样多的磁盘，
assuming I break up in a column store table
假设我在列存储表中拆分，
and every attribute goes to a separate, goes to a separate disk,
每个属性转到单独的磁盘，
would that be as fast as a row store.
这会和行存储一样快吗。
Well, no, because you have to,
不，因为你必须要做，
you still have to do that, that that splitting apart and writing it all out, right,
你还是要做那个分裂，然后写出来，
and then you also would have more pressure in memory,
然后你也会有更多的内存压力，
because, because again, say I have a thousand attributes,
因为，假设我有一千个属性，
so now if I have to update a thousand pages,
所以现在，如果我必须更新一千个页面，
I have thousand pages in my buffer pool
我的缓冲池中有一千个页面，
to do the update, to put each,
进行更新，
updating each of them with a new attribute
使用一个新的属性更新它们，
and then write them all out, right,
然后将它们全部写出来，
typically, again, doing updates in a, in a, in a column store system
通常，在列存储系统中更新，
without this sort of buffer thing I just mentioned
在没有我刚才提到的这种缓冲区的情况下，
is always going to be slow.
总是很慢的。
Yes.
是的。
Her question is,
她的问题是，
what is the null bitmap is there equivalence in, in, in row store,
在行存储中，什么是与 null bitmap 相对应的，
yeah, we discussed this last class,
是的，我们上节课讨论过了，
it basically, it's a way to represent which attribute is null, right,
它是一种表示哪个属性为空的方式，
so I'm not drawing here,
我没有在这里画出来，
but the header, the diagram last class,
上一节课的 header ，图表，
in the header of every row,
在每行的 header 中，
there'll be a bitmap and says which attribute is null or not, right,
都有一个 bitmap ，说明哪个属性是空的，
that's one approach to do it in this common one,
这是一种你可以做到的常规的方法，
you could do this,
你可以这样做，
we talk about the special value or each attribute,
我们谈论特定值或每个属性，
you could have a little flag in front of it,
你可以在它前面放一个小标志，
the null bitmap that basically says attribute,
null bitmap 基本上表示属性，
you know for this tuple, attribute one is null, attribute two is null
对于这个 tuple ，属性一是空，属性二是空，
and so think of that,
所以想一想，
instead of having that bitmap per, in the header per tuple,
不是在每个 tuple 的 header 中有 bitmap ，
in the column store, for the entire column, here's the null bitmap.
在列存储中，对于整个列，这是 null bitmap 。
Yes.
是的。
For an index in a His question is,
他的问题是，
in a column store,
在列存储中，
in column store, what does the index actually do,
在列存储中，索引是做什么的，
so some systems, some OLAP systems that are column stores,
所以一些 OLAP 系统是列存储，
you don't get any indexes,
你不会有任何索引，
I don't think Snowflake gives you an index,
我不认为 Snowflake 给了你索引，
you can't, you can't create one,
你不能创建一个，
it might have changed [], you couldn't have indexes, right,
它可能已经改变了[]，你不能有索引，
because again, they're not trying to do point queries or single single thing lookups,
因为，他们并不是试图进行点查询或单一事物查找，
to do complete scans.
来进行完整的扫描。
And so now you have the point and you are correct,
所以现在你说到点子上了，你是对的，
you could have indexes that are range indexes, right,
你可以拥有范围索引，
so here's where to find if your ID is when 0 and 100 go to this page,
所以，如果你的 ID 是 0 和 100 ，可以在这里找到这个页面，
there's things like that,
有这样的东西，
there's inverted indexes, like find all the the records where the keyword Andy exists, right,
有倒排索引，比如在所有记录中查找关键字 Andy ，
then that doesn't look like a tree structure,
这看起来不像是树形结构，
that's usually a hash table,
这通常是一个哈希表，
there's different types of indexes,
有不同类型的索引，
but you would not,
但你不会，
maybe you wouldn't have the index of do point query lookups.
也许你不会有执行点查询查找的索引。
All right, cool.
好的，太酷了。
So let's jump back.
所以，让我们跳回去。
All right, so I was kind of [hand wavy] about this part here,
好的，我试图解释这部分，
where I said, okay,
我说，好的，
let me go fetch the page that has the hostname,
让我去获取包含 hostname 的页面，
run my WHERE clause, I'll get a bunch of matches,
运行我的 WHERE 子句，我会得到一堆匹配的，
and then let me go fetch the lastLogin page,
然后让我去获取 lastLogin 页面，
and then I had a magic way of finding the matches there, right,
然后我有了一种神奇的方法在那里找到匹配的东西，
how do they do that.
他们是怎么做到的。
Well, the two approaches.
好的，有两种方法。
The most common one is to do fixed-length offsets,
最常见的一种是进行固定长度的偏移，
and that means that the, the,
这意味着，
you identify rows not by a slot number,
你不是通过插槽编号来标识行，
but you identify you know unique tuples,
而是通过唯一 tuple 来标识，
this is why I don't want to say row versus instead of tuples record,
这就是为什么我不想说行代替 tuple 记录，
because what does a row look like in a column store,
因为列存储中的行是什么样子的，
tuple is the better term,
tuple 是更好的术语，
but the unique identifier for a tuple is going to be its offset within the table,
但是 tuple 的唯一标识符将是它在表中的偏移量，
so now if I'm at, like offset three in one column,
所以现在如果我在一个列中的偏移量 3 ，
I would then know how to, you know, jump to offset three and another column,
我就知道如何跳到偏移量 3 和另一列，
and then I can stitch that tuple back together,
然后我可以把 tuple 缝合在一起，
but again, this only works if the values are fixed-length,
但是，这仅在值是固定长度的情况下有效，
of course, what breaks that assumption,
当然，是什么打破了这一假设，
variable length VARCHAR strings, BLOB, text, right,
可变长度 VARCHAR 字符串， BLOB,  TEXT ，
so we'll talk about how to handle that in a second,
我们稍后将讨论如何处理，
so that that this approach, the fixed-length column one,
所以这种方法，固定长度的列，
that's the, that's the most common one.
这是最常见的。
A legacy approach is to use embedded IDs,
一种传统的方法是使用嵌入的 ID ，
where with every single value you have some unique tuple identifier,
其中每个值都有一些唯一的 tuple 标识符，
like, you know, sort of like the log-structure stuff,
比如，有点像日志结构，
like some counter being increment by one,
比如一些计数器加 1 ，
and then there's some index structure, that I'm not showing here,
然后有一些索引结构，我在这里没有展示，
where for a given record ID, for a given column,
对于给定的记录 ID ，给定的列，
it tells you where to jump to this.
它告诉你跳到哪里。
This is rare,
这很少见，
you probably shouldn't even mention it,
你可能根本不应该提它，
but like, it is one way to do it,
但是，这是一种方法，
there was some system I forget in the old days that did do this,
在过去，我忘记了，一些系统确实做了这个，
because they were kind of like contorting a row store to make it a column store,
因为它们有点像是[扭曲]行存储，使其成为列存储，
but everyone uses fixed-length [] sets,
但每个都用固定长度集合，
of course, the problem you got to deal with now again is,
当然，你现在要再次处理的问题是，
how to convert variable length values into fixed-length values.
如何将可变长度值转换为固定长度值，
Let me think, I guess, how you do that.
让我想想，你如何做到这个。
Yes.
是的。
He says pointers, pointers to what?
他说指针，指向什么？
For every, every data is less continuous,
对于每个不连续的数据。
Yeah, that would, yeah, that actually would, would potentially work,
是的，这可能会奏效，
the problem with that one is like,
这个版本的问题是，
you to do like in place updates, right,
你做就地更新，
if you're just packing all the data in,
如果你只是把所有的数据打包，
if it's immutable, you don't have this problem,
如果它是不变的，你就不会有这个问题，
but if it is mutable, then you have fragmentation.
但如果它是可变的，那么你就有了碎片化。
He says slot arrays,
他说是 slot array ，
but what it pointing to.
但是它指向什么。
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
That sort of similar what he was saying, that potentially would work,
这与他所说的有点类似，有可能奏效，
compression, right.
压缩。
So the the point approach that would work,
所以，这个方法将会奏效，
I don't think anybody does that,
我不认为有人这么做，
you could just pad things out,
你可以把东西填满，
but that's going to be wasteful as we said before,
但就像我们之前说的那样，那将是浪费的，
but this is basically how dictionary compression works,
但这基本上就是[字典压缩]的工作方式，
dictionary compression is is replacing some, some variable length value with, with the integer code,
字典压缩是用整型代码来替换一些可变长度值，
which which is going to be fixed-length and usually 32 bits,
它是固定长度的，通常是 32 位，
that we can use to, to, to then do some predicates on the dictionary code
我们可以在字典代码上做一些[谓词]，
and if necessary, if it matches something we're looking for,
如果有必要，如果它匹配我们寻找的东西，
go do a lookup and find, find what the actual value is,
去查找，找出实际的值是什么，
and that's a typo,
这是一个打字错误，
it's not more in this next week,
它不是更多在下周，
it's more this hour, like we will discuss this now.
它更多在这个小时，我们现在就会讨论。
So, that's how we're going to be able to solve this problem,
这就是我们如何能够解决这个问题，
and pretty much the way everyone does it, in a modern system.
以及几乎每个人在现代系统中解决问题的方式。
So this [] idea is not new,
这种[]的想法并不是新的，
according to the literature,
根据文献记载，
the very first version of this goes back to 1970s,
最早的版本可以追溯到 1970 年代，
there is this project out of the the Swedish Defense Ministry called Cantor,
瑞典国防部有一个名为 Cantor 的项目，
it was more of a file system than a than a database system,
与其说它是一个数据库系统，不如说它是一个文件系统，
but this is considered to be the first documented like proposal for a column store system,
但这被认为是第一个记录在案的关于列存储系统的类似提案，
and I I don't know whether it, it, it, it exists today,
我不知道它今天是否存在，
in the 1980s, there was a paper that actually sort of mapped out
在 1980 年代，有一篇论文实际描绘了
the theoretical properties of what the decomposition storage model looked like,
分解存储模型的理论性质，
but again it was still mostly only only in academia,
但是，它在很大程度上仍然只是在学术界，
the roughly what considered the first commercial implementation of a column store system
被认为是列存储系统的第一个商业实现
was this thing called SybaseIQ,
是一个被称为 SybaseIQ 的东西，
but it wasn't really a full-fledged database system,
但它并不是一个真正成熟的数据库系统，
it was more like a like a query accelerator,
它更像是一个查询加速器，
and so similar to what I was saying before about Oracle,
与我之前提到的 Oracle 类似，
they make a copy of your row store into a in-memory column store,
它们将行存储的副本复制到内存中列存储中，
this is basically what Sybase was doing back in the 1990s,
这基本上就是 Sybase 在 1990 年代做的事情，
so your query would show up
所以，你的查询将会出现，
and then Sybase would figure out,
然后 Sybase 会计算出，
should I go to the row store and maybe do something there
我应该去行存储，并可能在那里做一些事情，
or should I run the query only on the, on the in-memory column store.
或者我应该只在内存中列存储上运行查询。
In the 2000s, is when the column store stuff really took off,
在 2000 年，是列存储真正起飞的时候，
and the three key systems in this space,
这个领域的三个关键系统，
where Vertica, which found by [], stands, Mike Stonebraker,
由 [] 创建， Mike Stonebraker ，
Vectorwise was a [] DB, but that was at a CWI
Vectorwise 是一个 [] 数据库，它是 CWI 的，
and MonetDB was was was a major academic project at CWI as well,
MonetDB 也是 CWI 的一个重要学术项目，
DuckDB is from CWI,
DuckDB 来自 CWI ，
so the the first version of DuckDB was actually called MonetDBLite,
DuckDB 的第一个版本实际上被称为 MonetDBLite ，
they threw all the code away
他们扔掉了所有的代码，
and then started DuckDB from scratch, after learning MonetDBLite,
然后从头开始 DuckDB ，在了解了 MonetDBLite 之后，
Vectorwise was started by some people that worked on MonetDB
Vectorwise 是由一些在 MonetDB 工作的人创办的，
and then the the two main people at Vectorwise,
然后 Vectorwise 的两个主要人员，
one of them left and was a co-founder of Snowflake,
其中一个离开了，是 Snowflake 的联合创始人，
so a lot of the early ideas that Vectorwise developed is in Snowflake
所以， Vectorwise 提出的许多早期想法都在 Snowflake ，
and then the other guy, Peter Boncz,
然后另一个人， Peter Boncz ，
he went back to CWI
他回到了 CWI ，
and then he, you know, helped advise the the DuckDB project.
然后，他帮助建议 DuckDB 项目。
So there was a bunch of other systems at the time,
所以当时有很多其他的系统，
but I consider these three major ones, the pioneers in this space.
但我认为这三个主要的系统是这个领域的先驱者。
And actually how this all sort of came out,
实际上，这一切出来，
the way Mike tells it was, or Stonebraker tells it,
Mike 说的，或者 Stonebraker 说的方法，
he was consulting for Walmart Labs, in the early 2000s,
他是沃尔玛实验室的顾问，在 2000 年代早期，
and they were struggling try to scale their tera data database,
他们努力扩大他们的 TB 数据库，
at the time was a row store,
当时是行存储，
I think Walmart was, it was multiple petabytes,
我认为沃尔玛是多个 PB ，
it was a database of every single transaction,
它是每一笔交易的数据库，
anytime somebody bought something at a store,
任何时候，当有人在商店购买东西，
like [], it was in that database
比如[]，它就在那个数据库中，
and they were struggling to get tera data to run fast,
他们努力让 TB 数据运行更快，
and then Mike was like,
然后迈克想，
oh, we should make just make this the column store
哦，我们应该把这个做成列存储，
and then he, and then he he founded the C-store project, that became Vectica
然后他创立了 C-store 项目，后来变成了 Vectica ，
and then, it was a pretty famous project.
然后，这是一个非常著名的项目。
Now pretty much everybody does this,
现在几乎每个人都这么做了，
so this is just a sample of a bunch of database systems that are out there, that are considered column stores,
这只是一些被认为是列存储的数据库系统中的一个示例，
but the two key things that are also interesting about the 2010 is,
但是 2010 年还有两件很有趣的事情，
there's these open source file formats, Parquet and ORC,
那就是有这些开源的文件格式， Parquet 和 ORC ，
parquet came out of Dremio and somebody else I'm forgetting
Parquet 来自 Dremio 和另一个我忘记的人，，
and ORC came out of Facebook,
ORC 来自 Facebook ，
these are open source file formats that are columnar based,
这些都是基于列的开源文件格式，
and now you can build database systems that can read and write Parquet ORC files.
现在你可以构建读写 Parquet ORC 文件的数据库系统。
All right, so the advantages for the, the columnar or decomposition storage model is that,
好的，列或分解存储模型的优势在于，
we're going to greatly reduce the amount of waste I/O,
我们将极大地减少 I/O 浪费的数量，
we have to do for analytical queries,
我们进行分析查询所需的，
because we're only reading the exact data that we need,
因为我们只读取所需的数据，
and we're going to get better cache for use
我们将获得更好的缓存使用
and better locality for our access patterns,
和更好的访问模式位置，
because again, we're literally just going to rip through columns one after another
因为，我们实际上只需要一个接一个地[撕裂]列，
and not have to jump around within, within memory,
而不必在内存中跳跃，
which is better for CPUs,
这对 CPU 更好，
and again, we'll get better compression,
同样，我们将获得更好的压缩，
which we're coming up to.
这是我们要讲到的。
Because the downside is going to be,
这是因为缺点是，
it's going to be slow for point query,
点查询的速度会很慢，
slow for insert update delete,
插入，更新，删除的速度会很慢，
because we're going to have to split things up
因为我们将不得不拆分数据，
and write out multiple, you know, data to multiple locations
并将多个数据写到多个位置，
and then bring it back in
然后再带回它，
if we want to put it, put it back together.
如果我们想把它放在一起。
Yes.
是的。
Question is, [] build their own database, no,
问题是，[]是否建立了自己的数据库，没有，
it consider that an each [],
它认为每个[]，
but [] DB is real, that's a real system.
但[]数据库是真实的，是一个真正的系统。
Okay.
好的。
So one thing to point out, though, is that,
所以，有一点需要指出的是，
in my, my earlier example,
在我前面的例子中，
the way I showed I ran that one query,
我展示了我运行一个查询，
I did the scan on the, on the, on the, on the the hostname the column,
我在 hostname 列上进行了扫描，
then I ran the scan portion of the query on the on the login one
然后，我在 login 上运行了查询的扫描部分，
and you sort of think of that,
你可以想象一下，
like it was I did one and then it moved on another,
就像我做了一个，然后它又移动到另一个，
a lot of cases though, queries,
但是，在很多情况下的查询，
you actually want to look at multiple columns at the same time, right,
你希望同时查看多个列，
my WHERE clause had was only referenced one attribute,
我的 WHERE 子句只引用了一个属性，
but as you've seen in the queries you've written for homework one,
但像你在为家庭作业一编写的查询中看到的那样，
often times you have multiple columns or multiple attributes referenced in your WHERE clause,
通常，你在 WHERE 子句中经常引用了多个列或多个属性，
and so it would be kind of kind of expensive or cumbersome to sort of now maintaining,
所以，现在维护会有点昂贵或繁琐，
as I'm scanning along one column, fetching in another column at the same time
因为我沿着一列扫描，同时获取另一列，
and trying to patch things together,
并试图将东西拼凑在一起，
and so we still want we still, we want to be able to have data
所以我们仍然希望有数据，
or we want, we want a way
我们想要一种方式，
to have the attributes that are somewhat that are going to use together
让在一起使用的属性，
somewhat close to each other on disk in our files,
在我们的文件中彼此靠近的磁盘上，
but still get all the benefit of a column store layout, right.
但仍然可以获得列存储布局的所有好处。
And so this is what the PAX model, model is,
这就是 PAX 模型，
again, and as I said,
正如我所说的，
in most systems, they say they're a column store,
在大多数系统中，他们说他们是一个列存储，
they're really doing this,
他们是这么做的，
Parquet and ORC are really, really doing this.
Parquet 和 ORC 是这样做的。
And the idea is not like, you know, mind blowing,
这个想法不是令人振奋的，
it just basically saying,
它只是说，
instead of having a separate file for every single column or attribute by itself,
不是每个单独的列或属性都有一个单独的文件，
I'll have, I'll break them up into chunks, into row groups
我会把它们分成块，分成行组，
and have data that are within the same tuple close to each other,
让同一个 tuple 里的数据彼此接近，
in the same file, just sort of spaced out in separate pages, right.
在同一个文件中，只是在不同的页面中隔开了一些。
So if we go back to our sort of mock example here,
所以，如果我们回到我们这里的模拟示例，
all we're going to do is just horizontally partition the table into to row groups,
我们要做的就是将表水平分区到行组中，
and then within that row group,
然后在行组中，
we're going to partition it based on columns, right.
我们将根据列对其进行分区，
So you think of this, the first three rows here,
所以，你想想这里的前三行，
I'll have some portion in my giant file, define the row group,
我在我的巨大文件中有一些部分定义行组，
I have a header for that row group
我有那个行组的 header ，
and then I have all the attribute of column A together,
然后我把列 A 的所有属性都放在一起，
then all the attributes for all the values for column A,
然后是列 A 的所有值，
all the values column B,
列 B 的所有值，
followed by all the values column C, right.
以及列 C 的所有值。
So now again, if I have a WHERE clause
所以现在如果我有一个 WHERE 子句，
that needs to access, you know, both column A and column C,
需要访问列 A 和列 C ，
when I go fetch these pages for this row group,
当我去获取这个行组的这些页面时，
I, you know, I I have all the data for that I need close to each other,
我有我需要的所有数据靠在一起，
but I'm also getting the benefit [] I/O,
我也得到了[] I/O 的好处，
because this row group is gonna be, you know, in in the tens of megabytes
因为这个行组将以几十兆字节的形式存在，
instead of like, you know, four kilobyte or eight kilobyte pages, right,
而不是 4 千字节或 8 千字节的页面，
same thing with the next guy, and so forth.
下一个也是这样，诸如此类。
And so, this is roughly how Parquet work,
所以，这大概就是 Parquet 的工作原理，
there's a lot of diagrams or presentations of what Parquet look look like,
有很多 Parquet 看起来是什么样子的图表或演示，
and again, they're basically using all the same language that that we're using here,
他们基本上使用了我们在这里使用的所有相同的语言，
and here they say the, the default size of a page is one megabyte,
这里他们说，页面的默认大小是 1 兆字节，
because they want to have, you know, group things together
因为他们想要把东西组合在一起，
and have, you know, as much stretch I/O as they can,
并尽可能多地[伸缩] I/O ，
and then a row groupp is going to be 128 megabytes.
然后一个行组将是 128 兆字节。
Yes.
是的。
The statement is,
问题是，
couldn't this also have you still have the problem where you have a bunch of I/Os,
这难道不是仍然有很多 I/O 的问题，
if you're doing a full table scan.
如果你在做全表扫描时。
The header tells you where things are, right,
header 告诉你东西在哪里，
and because it's so huge,
因为它是如此之大，
like I could bring in, I bring in this first header here,
我在这里带来入第一个 header ，
actually, I'm showing the header,
我显示的是 header ，
but like in in real systems or in Parquet Orc,
但是在真实系统或 Parquet Orc 中，
it's actually at the footer,
它实际上位于 footer ，
because assuming the file is immutable,
因为假设文件是不可变的，
so I don't know what like,
所以我不知道会是什么样子，
I don't know what where everything's gonna be until I finish writing it,
我不知道一切会是什么样子，直到我写完它，
so it's in the footer,
所以它在 footer ，
but that's an aside,
但这是一个次要问题，
so his statement is,
所以他的问题是，
don't have the same problem as a row store here,
不会有和这里的行存储一样的问题，
if I'm doing this PAX thing,
如果我做这个 PAX 的事情，
because now if I bring this entire row group in,
因为现在如果我把整个行组都带入进来，
am I going to read a bunch of stuff I don't need,
我是不是要读一大堆我不需要的东西，
so you don't bring the whole row group in,
所以你不会把整个行组都带进来，
you bring the header in
你把 header 带进来，
and you say here's the offsets now of where my attributes are
说这是我的属性所在位置的偏移量，
and then go ahead and fetch those.
然后继续去取那些。
Actually, here you can see,
实际上，你可以在这里看到，
here, here's you see the footer here instead of the header,
这里，你看到的是 footer ，而不是 header ，
the metadata, what's in here,
元数据在这里，
the file and column metadata, what the offsets are,
文件和列元数据，偏移量在哪里，
instead of the header, it's just in the footer,
不是在 header ，而是在 footer ，
for Parquet and Orc is the same way.
对于 Parquet 和 Orc 也是一样的。
All right, so, as you say multiple times,
好的，所以，正如你多次提到的，
I/O has always been the main bottleneck we have,
I/O 一直是我们的主要瓶颈，
especially for analytical queries
尤其是在分析查询时，
and if we assume the data uncompressed,
如果我们假设数据未被压缩，
that means like the,
那就意味着，
you know, whatever the exact size of a tuple for in a table,
无论表中 tuple 的确切大小是多少，
every page is going to bring exactly that data in,
每个页面都会带来确切的数据，
and so the most obvious way to reduce the,
所以，减少的最明显方法是，
to speed up queries, you can, you can, you can basically skip data
为了加快查询，你可以跳过数据，
or you can make the data you do fetch, bring more things into memory.
或者你可以让你提取的数据，把更多的东西放入内存。
So skipping data is what the column store stuff helps with,
所以，跳过数据是列存储的帮助，
because you avoid having to read attributes you don't need,
因为你不必读取不需要的属性，
compression is another way,
压缩是另一种方法，
to say, okay, for every page I fetch,
说，好的，对于我获取的每个页面，
I get more tuples than I would if it was uncompressed.
我得到的比未压缩的页面更多的 tuple ，
now this is going to be this trade off between speed up and the compression ratio,
现在，这将是速度和压缩率之间的权衡，
obviously disk is going to be potentially slower than CPU,
显然，磁盘可能会比 CPU 慢，
especially in the cloud setting,
尤其是在云环境中，
and so I'm willing to pay the extra cost of having to decompress and compress data,
我需要支付必须解压缩和压缩数据的额外成本，
because now again it reduce my amount of IOPS,
因为现在这又一次减少了我的 IOPS 数量，
amount of time I'm wasting on IOPS to bring to fetch things in.
我在 IOPS 上浪费的取东西的时间。
Things are slightly getting,
事情略微变得，
the sort of, the difference between disk and CPU speed is getting, the distance is getting smaller,
磁盘和 CPU 速度差距变小，
where in some cases, disk is actually getting so fast lately,
在某些情况下，磁盘最近变得如此之快，
where maybe you don't want things to be compressed.
而你可能不希望东西被压缩。
There'll be some other benefits we'll see in a second,
我们很快就会看到一些其他的好处，
where we do keep things compressed,
我们保持压缩，
the database system actually can run faster,
数据库系统可以运行得更快，
when it actually processes things in memory,
当它在内存中处理东西时，
and we'll cover that in a few weeks,
我们将在几周内讨论这个，
but in general, for most systems,
但总的来说，对于大多数系统来说，
compressing things on disk is, is always going to be a win.
压缩磁盘上的数据总是一件好事。
So, any compression scheme we need to use has to produce fixed-length values,
所以，我们需要使用的任何压缩方案都必须产生固定的长度值，
as we said before,
正如我们前面所说的，
because we want to store this in a column store,
因为我们希望将其存储在列存储中，
we want to make sure that we always have fixed-length all sets.
我们希望确保所有集合都是固定长度。
In some cases, too,
在某些情况下，
we want to delay, when we actually decompress things for as long as possible,
我们希望延迟尽可能长的时间，当我们解压缩时，
while we execute queries
当我们执行查询时，
and we'll see this again,
我们会再次看到这个，
we'll talk about this more when we talk about query execution,
我们将在讨论查询执行时更多地讨论这个，
but the idea here is that,
但这里的想法是，
if I have a bunch of these one megabyte strings,
如果我有一堆 1 兆字节的字符串，
that that are in my table,
在我的表里，
but I can, I can convert them to 32 bit integers,
但是我可以把它们转换成 32 位整数，
I want to process 32 bit integers for as long as possible,
我希望尽可能长地处理 32 位整数，
because I have to copy data from one operator to the next,
因为我必须将数据从一个运算符复制到下一个，
as, as I execute the query,
当我执行查询时，
or if it's a distributed system copied over the network,
或者如果它是通过网络复制的分布式系统，
I want to keep things that compress as long as possible
我希望尽可能长地保持压缩的内容，
and only decompress it when I actually have to show something back to,
只有在我必须显示的时候才将其解压缩，
that something needs it to be decompressed
某些东西需要它被解压，
or the user needs the output,
或者用户需要输出，
JOINs makes that, makes that harder,
JOIN 使这个变得更加困难，
but we'll cover that later in a second.
我们稍后将会讨论。
And then the most important thing we need for any compression scheme in our data system is,
然后，对于我们的数据系统中的任何压缩方案最重要的是，
we need to ensure that we're using a lossless scheme,
我们需要确保我们使用的是无损方案，
anyone know what that means,
有人知道这是什么意思吗，
lossy versus lossless.
有损对无损。
Yes.
是的。
Right, there's no information loss when you compress things, right, or decompress them, right,
正确，当你压缩或解压时，信息不会丢失，
so a lossy scheme would be like MP3, MP4, JPEG,
一个有损方案就像是 MP3 MP4 JPEG ，
where they're doing some tricks about how the human perceives, you know, audio data or visual data
他们在做一些关于人类如何感知音频数据或视频数据的技巧，
to compress things down to a much smaller size,
将东西压缩到更小的尺寸，
so that means if you have the raw image you took and the raw sound file you took,
这意味着如果你有你拍摄的原始图像和原始声音文件，
when you compress it,
当你压缩它的时候，
you're not going to get back the same, the same values,
你不会得到相同的值，
if you will, when you decompress it.
当你解压缩它的时候。
We don't want to do that in a database system,
我们不想在数据库系统中这样做，
because, but as you said before, people don't losing data, right,
因为，就像你之前说的，人们不会丢失数据，
if, you know, if you have 100 dollars in your bank account
如果你的银行账户中有 100 美元，
and then they compress the data
然后他们压缩数据，
and when it gets decompress and now you have, you know, 90 dollars,
当数据被解压缩时，现在你有 90 美元，
you're gonna notice, you're gonna complain, right,
你会注意到，你会抱怨，
so typically, you know, most systems will not use a lossy scheme just,
所以，通常情况下，大多数系统不会使用有损方案，
because you know it'll have problems.
因为它会有问题。
You can do lossy compression yourself, right,
你自己可以使用有损方案，
so think of like, I mean like the application could do this,
所以想想，我的意思是，应用程序可以做这个，
like if I have, keeping track of the temperature of this room every second, right,
比如如果我每秒都在记录这个房间的温度，
and I do this for for ten years,
我这样做了十年，
do I really need to know what the exact temperature was
我真的需要知道当时的确切温度吗，
at, at a one second interval, you know, a year from now,
在一年后的某一秒时间，
no, I could maybe compress it down to,
不，我可以把它压缩到，
here's the average temperature per minute, right.
这是每分钟的平均温度。
So I can't get back the original data,
我无法恢复原始数据，
because it been compressed or aggregated,
因为它已被压缩或聚合，
and that might be okay.
这可能没有问题。
But again, that's something you as a user in the application,
但是，这是作为应用程序中的用户，
a human has to know whether that's an okay thing to do,
人必须知道事情是否可以做，
the database system doesn't,
数据库系统做不到，
therefore, the database system is always going to be using a lossless scheme.
所以，数据库系统总是使用无损方案。
So now the question is,
所以现在的问题是，
what do we actually want to compress,
我们想要压缩什么，
and there's, there's a couple different choices.
这里有几个不同的选择。
One is we can compress a single page or a block of data,
一是我们可以压缩单个页面或一块数据，
so that's all the tuples within the same table.
这是一个表上的所有 tuple 。
We can compress a single tuple by itself,
我们可以单独压缩一个 tuple ，
if it's a row store system.
如果它是行存储系统。
We can go even more fine grain than that,
我们甚至可以做更细的粒度，
we can say I compress within one tuple,
我们可以说我在一个 tuple 中压缩，
one single attribute and compress that,
压缩一个属性，
so think of like the overflow tables, we said before,
想象我们之前说过的溢出表，
if you're storing huge text attributes
如果你在存储巨大的文本属性，
or in Wikipedia, the revisions could be a lot of text,
或在维基百科中，修订可能是大量的文本，
I forget what the largest Wikipedia article is
我忘记了维基百科上最大的文章是什么，
and it's something star wars,
它是星球大战的东西，
so that, you know, could be kilobytes of text data,
所以，可能是千字节的文本数据，
and I could compress just for that, you know, that one entry,
我可以为对它进行压缩，那个条目，
and Postgres do this and a bunch of other systems do this,
Postgres 这样做的，还有一堆其他系统这样做。
Or alternatively, I could compress for a single column,
或者，我也可以压缩单个列，
if it's a column store system.
如果它是列存储系统。
So let's talk about how you can do this at the block level,
所以让我们讨论一下如何在块级别上做到这个，
and then we'll spend most our time talking how to do this at the column level,
然后我们将花大部分时间来讨论如何在列级别上做到这个，
because that matters the most for in a column store system.
因为这对于列存储系统来说是最重要的。
So to do it at a block level,
所以，要在数据块级别上做到这个，
we, we essentially need to use a naive compression scheme,
我们需要使用简单的压缩方案，
and by naive I mean that the,
我说的简单，我的意思是，
it's, it's the database system is making a call to like a third party library like Gzip,
它是数据库系统调用类似于 Gzip 的第三方库，
you wouldn't want to use that, because it's slow,
你不会想要使用它，因为它很慢，
but it's a third party library,
但它是一个第三方库，
that's going to take the page and then compress it down to some binary form,
它将获取页面，然后将其压缩成某种二进制形式，
where the database system has no way to interpret
数据库系统无法解释，
or can do any introspection into the compressed version of, of the block, right,
或自省到块的压缩版本，
again, so I call, you know, call Gzip on a, on a, on a file,
所以在一个文件上调用 Gzip ，
the database system doesn't know how to go read inside that compress file, right,
数据库系统不知道如何读取压缩文件中的内容，
it has to decompress it
它必须对其进行解压缩，
in order to get back the original version of it, right.
才能恢复其原始版本。
So again, you wouldn't want to use Gzip,
你不会想要使用 Gzip ，
there's a bunch of these faster alternatives
有一堆这样更快的替代方案，
and that sort of all came out with LZO,
它们都来自 LZO ，
was was a big great breakthrough in the in 1990s,
是 1990 年代一个巨大的突破，
Zstd is considered the state of the art compression scheme now,
Zstd 被认为是最先进的压缩方案，
from Facebook,
来自 Facebook ，
they're actually working on a new version. It's not public yet,
他们正在开发一个新版本，它还没有公开，
it's even faster and better,
它更快更好，
but that's not out yet,
但这还没有出来，
but Zstd is what you should be using.
但是 Zstd 是你要使用的。
So let's see how MySQL does this,
所以，让我们来看看 MySQL 是如何做的这个，
so MySQL, you can support table compression,
所以 MySQL 操作，你可以支持表压缩，
you declare it on a per table basis,
你在每个表的基础上声明它，
I don't think it's owned by default,
我不认为它是默认的，
and the way it works is that,
它的工作方式是，
all your your pages when they're written, a disk,
当你的所有页面被写入磁盘时，
they're going to be compressed into into some page size,
它们将被压缩成页面大小，
that some multiple of, of of 4 or 2, up to 8 kilobytes,
是 4 或 2 ，最多 8 千字节，
and in each page,
在每个页面中，
they're going to have a header portion called the mod log,
他们将有一个 header 部分，称为 mod log ，
where it's sort of like the row store thing I mentioned before,
这有点像我之前提到的行存储，
where I can do a bunch of writes and make changes to the page
我可以在那里进行一系列写入和对页面进行更改，
without having to decompress it first, right,
而不必先解压缩它，
so it's like a little extra space in the beginning.
所以这就像是开始有一点额外的空间。
And I would say also too,
我也会说，
say like say if your page is like when compressed, it's 6 kilobytes,
比如，如果你的页面在压缩后是 6 千字节，
they'll pad it up to the next highest value within one, two, four, eight,
他们会将其填充到 1，2，4，8 中的下一个最高值，
and this ensures that you have, you don't have any fragmentation in, in your layout on disk,
这确保你在磁盘上的布局中没有任何碎片，
and, and when you bring things into memory.
当你把东西带入内存时。
So say I, I query runs
假设我运行了一个查询，
and want to read something in page 0, right,
想要读取页 0 中的内容，
if I'm doing a blind write,
如果我执行一个盲写操作，
like an insert or a delete or even update,
比如插入、删除甚至更新，
assuming I have the values,
假设我有这些值，
I don't need to decompress the page,
我就不需要解压缩页面，
I just write that change to the mod log
我只是将更改写入 mod log ，
and again it's just a log structure,
它是一个日志结构，
like we talked about before,
就像我们之前谈到的那样，
I said we going to see this idea throughout the rest of the semester,
我说我们会在这学期剩下的时间里看到这个想法，
you can think the mod log is just the log structure storage we talked about before.
你可以认为 mod log 就是我们前面谈到的日志结构存储。
And in some cases too,
在某些情况下，
I can do reads on the mod log,
我也可以对 mod log 进行读取，
because if the data I need was just inserted and within the mod log,
因为如果我需要的数据只是插入到 mod log 中，
I don't have to decompress the rest of the page,
我就不必解压缩页面的其余部分，
but then if I do need to read the page,
但如果我确实需要读取页面，
they'll, they'll decompress it,
他们会将其解压缩，
store it as a regular 16 kilobyte page in in memory, in the buffer pool,
将其作为常规的 16 千字节页面存储在内存中，缓冲池中，
because that's the default size for MySQL,
因为这是 MySQL 的默认大小，
and then I can do whatever reads I want on that, right,
然后我可以对其执行任何读取操作，
but I still keep the compressed version around
但我仍然保留压缩版本，
and I think also too,
我也认为，
when it gets decompressed,
当它被解压缩时，
they apply the changes to the mod log to to the page there, right.
他们会将对 mod log 的更改应用到那里的页面，
This is a good idea or a bad idea?
这是一个好主意，还是一个坏主意？
Postgres doesn't do this.
Postgres 没有这样做。
Yes.
是的。
He said, so reading it's not super great, why?
他说，读取不是很好，为什么，
Not necessarily,
不一定，
like, like going back here,
比如回到这里，
if I do an insert,
如果我做插入的话，
and it lands in the mod log, right,
然后它落在 mod log 中，
I don't have to decompress it,
我不需要解压缩它，
my index,
我的索引，
like there's some bookkeeping doing saying,
比如这里有[记录]表示，
okay, I updated the index now,
好的，我现在更新了索引，
so the record ID points to this page
所以 record ID 指向这个页面，
and then you look in the mod log,
然后你可以查看 mod log ，
oh, for that slot number, that that record ID,
对于那个插槽号，那个 record ID ，
it's really in the mod log, the [full] page,
它在 mod log 中，那个页面，
so you don't have to decompress it.
这样你就不必解压缩了。
I'll say I actually think it's a decent idea,
我会说，我觉得这是个不错的主意，
and, and I say, Postgres doesn't do it,
而且，我说， Postgres 没有做这个，
not because,
不是因为，
like, oh, Postgres, like Postgres is not the Gospel, right,
哦， Postgres 不是福音，
Postgres doesn't do something,
Postgres 没有做某事，
doesn't mean like you shouldn't be doing it,
并不意味着你不应该做这件事，
Postgres is actually amazing front end,
Postgres 有令人惊叹的前端，
the back end is actually pretty terrible, right,
后端实际上相当糟糕，
because a lot of the design is remnants from the 1980s,
因为很多设计都是 1980 年代的残余物，
and it's not how you would build a modern system today,
这不是你今天构建现代系统的方式，
so, and they don't support compression for, for regular data pages like this,
所以，他们不支持对于常规数据页面的压缩，
only for TOAST tables, the overflow pages,
只支持 TOAST 表，溢出页面，
so this is actually a decent idea, right.
所以，这实际上是一个不错的想法。
It does have some challenges, though, right,
不过，它确实有一些挑战，
because MySQL is a row store,
因为 MySQL 是行存储，
the that's why you have to use naive compression scheme,
这就是为什么你必须使用简单的压缩方案，
because you can't do anything fancy,
因为你不能做任何奇妙的事情，
because the, the values you're storing in the tuples themselves or sorry in the page itself
因为你存储在 tuple 本身或页面本身中的值，
from all the different attributes
来自所有不同的属性，
and you're not going to be able to do all the native compression,
你不能进行所有的简单压缩，
we'll see in a second, right.
我们一会儿就会看到。
And again, because we're just using, I think they use Snappy or Zstd,
因为我们只是使用，我想他们使用的 Snappy 或 Zstd ，
because we're using a general purpose compression algorithm,
因为我们使用的是通用压缩算法，
the database system doesn't know how to interpret
数据库系统不知道如何解释
what those compressed version, compressed bytes actually mean.
这些压缩版本、压缩字节的实际含义。
And the spoiler is all those compression algorithms I've talked about before,
搅局的是我之前谈到的所有压缩算法，
they're basically doing some variant of of dictionary compression,
它们基本上是字典压缩的一些变体，
it's going to build its own dictionary of repeated byte byte sequences,
它将为重复的字节序列构建自己的字典，
but again, MySQL doesn't know how to read that dictionary,
但是， MySQL 不知道如何读取那个字典，
so it has to decompress the whole thing.
所以它必须解压缩整个东西。
So for some workloads, I think this, this is actually a good idea
所以，对于一些工作负载，我认为这是一个好主意，
and I kind of wish Postgres did do some compression.
我也希望 Postgres 做一些压缩。
All right, so, if we're doing OLAP,
好的，所以，如果我们做 OLAP ，
ideally, we want to be able to run our query directly in the compressed data
理想情况下，我们希望能够直接在压缩数据中运行查询，
without having to decompress it first, right.
而不必先将其解压缩。
So say something like this,
比如这样的东西，
I have my salary, DJ 2PL salary,
有我的工资， DJ 2PL 的工资，
assuming I have some compression algorithm,
假设我有一些压缩算法，
I'm not saying what it is
我没有说它是什么，
and then I have a compressed form of of the database,
然后我有了数据库的压缩形式，
well, if my query shows up,
好的，如果我的查询出现，
I want to get my salary,
我想获得我的工资，
I do some kind of magic that converts the query,
我使用了某种魔法转换查询，
to convert this constant string Andy into the compressed form,
将常量字符串 Andy 转换为压缩形式，
and now I can do a direct lookup on my compressed table
现在我可以在我的压缩表上进行直接查找，
using my compressed constant
使用我的压缩常量，
and not have to decompress every single page as I'm going along,
而不必在我前进的过程中解压缩每一页，
now I'm getting, I'm going to reduce amount of I/O I have to do,
现在我要减少我必须做的 I/O 的数量，
because I'm fetching and compress pages,
因为我获取和压缩页面，
I don't have to decompress them in order to do lookups into them.
我不需要解压缩它们来查找它们。
So this is idea what we want,
这就是我们想要的想法，
and the easiest way to do this is going to be in a columnar system.
实现这个的最简单方法是在列式系统中。
So this is just sort of a quick overview of a bunch of different compression algorithms you could possibly have.
所以这只是你可能有的一系列不同压缩算法的简单概述。
Again, the [spoil] is going to be dictionary compression,
这将是字典压缩，
dictionary encoding is the default choice for most systems,
字典编码是大多数系统的默认选择，
but what you can do,
但你可以做的是，
you may not want to compress a single column using these other schemes,
你可能不想使用这些其他方案压缩单个列，
we'll see some examples where it does make sense,
我们将看到一些它有意义的例子，
but after you do dictionary encoding,
但是在你进行字典编码之后，
you can apply all these other compression schemes on the dictionary itself,
你可以将所有这些其他压缩方案应用于字典本身，
or you're still your dictionary encoded values and get even further compression.
或者仍然你的字典编码值进行进一步的压缩。
So you can get sort of a multiplicative effect
所以你可以得到一种乘法效果，
where you do compression one way,
你以一种方式进行压缩，
and then you run another compression algorithm on the compressed data
然后对压缩的数据运行另一种压缩算法，
and get even better compression,
得到更好的压缩，
and it's still done in a way where the database system can natively interpret,
而且它仍然是以数据库系统可以简单解释的方式完成，
what those bytes actually mean in the compressed form,
这些字节在压缩形式中的实际含义，
without having to decompress it first.
而不必先将其解压缩。
And again, this is why you want the database system to do everything, do everything
这就是为什么你希望数据库系统做任何事情，
and don't want the OS to do anything or anybody else to do anything,
而不希望操作系统做任何事情或任何其他人做任何事情，
because, again, because we can do this native compression.
因为，因为我们可以进行简单压缩。
So let's do some quick examples here.
所以让我们在这里做一些快速的例子。
So one approach you do is called run-length encoding, RLE,
所以你做的一种方法叫做游程编码， RLE ，
and this is the basic idea here is that,
这里的基本思想是，
if we have contiguous runs of values that are the same thing,
如果我们有一系列连续的值是相同的，
literally the same value,
从字面上看是相同的值，
instead of storing that value over and over again for every single tuple,
不是为每个 tuple 一次又一次地存储那个值，
I'll instead store a compressed summary,
而是存储一个压缩的摘要，
that says for this value, at this offset,
对于这个值，在这个偏移量上，
here's how many, how many occurrences it has, right.
这里是它有多少出现。
Now, this works great,
那么这种方法非常有效，
if your data is sorted based on whatever the column you're trying to compress,
如果你的数据是根据你试图压缩的列进行排序的，
you can't always do this,
你不能总是这样做，
but again, if you sort things,
但是，如果你对东西进行排序，
then you can, you can maximize the amount of maximize the repeated runs.
那么你就可以最大化重复游程。
Let's say I I have a single table,
假设我有一个单独的表，
where it has an id field
其中有一个 id 字段，
and then has a column says whether somebody's dead or not,
然后有一个列，说明某人是否死了，
yes or no, right, Yes or no, there's no null, there's no maybe, right,
是或不是，没有 null ，没有可能，
so we can compress this guy here, right,
所以我们可以这样压缩，
so a compressed form
所以一个压缩的形式，
would just take, essentially just scanning through the column
基本上只需要扫描列，
and finding the contiguous attributes or tuples that have the same value
找到具有连续相同值的属性或 tuple ，
and then converting it into this triplet,
然后将其转换为这个三元组，
that says, here's the value, where at this offset, and here's the size of the run.
它说，这是值，在这个偏移量，这是游程的大小。
All right.
好的。
And so now if have a query comes along,
现在，如果有一个问题出现，
like count the number of people that are dead versus not dead, right,
比如计算死亡人数与未死亡人数，
I can just rip through that isDead column
我只需展开 isDead 列，
and compute my aggregation by just summing up the the length of the run,
并通过对行程长度求和来计算我的聚合，
you know, and then along with the value there.
然后和那里的值一起。
I actually can do even better, right,
事实上，我可以做得更好，
so I have this little, this little part here,
所以我这里有一个小的部分，
I have somebody's not dead,
我有一些人没有死，
and then they're dead and not dead,
然后又有一些死了，有一些没有死，
so I have now these three triplets here where the run size is 1,
所以我现在有三个三元组，游程大小是 1 ，
so in this case here, I'm actually doing worse,
所以在这个例子中，我实际上做得更糟，
because I'm, I'm storing a triplet,
因为我存储的是一个三元组，
when I could have just stored a single value by itself, right,
而我本来可以只存储一个值本身，
so if I sort the data based on whether somebody is dead or not,
所以，如果我根据某人是否死亡来对数据进行排序，
now my compression only has, you know, compressed column only has two entries,
现在我的压缩列只有两个条目，
here's all the dead people and here all the non dead people,
这里是所有的死的人，这里是所有没有死的人，
and this greatly reduces the amount of data at the store now.
这极大地减少了存储的数据量。
So it may be the case,
所以，情况可能是这样，
again say I have, always think of it extremes,
比如我有，总是认为它是极端的，
my example is,
我的例子是，
I have to fit them on the slides,
我必须把它们放在我的幻灯片上，
I having, I have ten, eight, eight or nine tuples here,
我这里有八九个 tuple ，
if I have a billion tuples or a billion people,
如果我有十亿个 tuple 或十亿个人，
I can compress now down,
我现在可以压缩，
you know, keeping track of like, you know who's a billion people was dead or not dead,
跟踪 10 亿人中谁死了，谁没有死，
into a small number of bytes,
到一小部分字节，
and that will fit on one page,
这将适合在一页上，
you need the length in the triplet,
你需要三元组中的长度，
because, because, again, assuming that we always have fixed length offsets,
因为，假设我们总是有固定长度的偏移量，
this allows you to figure out,
这可以让你计算出，
okay, like if I need to find for a single tuple, a single entry,
好的，如果我需要找到单个 tuple ，单一条目，
if they dead or not,
他们是否死了，
like it allows you to do the math to reverse it back
允许你做数学还原它，
and say, okay, I would be at this offset if I was uncompressed,
说，好的，如果我被解压缩，我会在这个偏移量上，
and that's just simple arithmetic.
这只是一个简单的算术。
Another compression scheme you can do is called bit packing,
你可以做的另一个压缩方法叫做位压缩，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
people often times declare attributes or columns in a certain type,
人们经常会声明某种类型的属性或列，
that is larger than they actually need,
比实际需要的要大，
so the idea would be,
假设想法是，
like if I have a column where I'm keeping track of some number,
我有一个列，跟踪某个数字，
and I declare it as an integer type,
我将它声明为一个整数类型，
that's, in SQL, that's, it's a 32 bit integer,
在 SQL 中，这是一个 32 位的整数，
so that means that,
这意味着，
even if, no matter if there's a small value,
即使有一个很小的值，
I'm still going to allocate 32 bits to store,
我仍然会分配 32 位来存储，
so for these numbers here,
所以对于这里的这些数字，
none of them are very big,
它们都不是很大，
but I'm always going to store it as certain bits,
但我总是会以固定位存储它，
so in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
to store these these eight or nine numbers, eight numbers,
为了存储这八九个数字，八个数字，
I store 256 bits,
我存储了 256 位，
but again, the only thing that matters is actually these lower portion of the bits here,
但是，唯一重要的是这里位的下部，
because this is, this is the actual, this is the actual data that I need, right,
因为，这是我需要的实际数据，
all this other stuff,
所有这些其他的东西，
you know, the other, the other 24 bits is just wasted space, right,
其他的 24 位都是浪费的空间，
so instead what I can do is,
所以我能做的是，
even though you declared it as a 32 bit integer,
即使你将其声明为 32 位整数，
I'm going to store it as an 8 bit integer,
我也会将其存储为 8 位整数，
and then now that greatly reduces the size down by a factor of four,
现在，这极大地缩小了四倍的大小，
so I was able to go again from 256 bits to 64 bits,
所以我能够从 256 位到 64 位，
and you can do a bunch of tricks with bit shifting operators and [],
你可以用位移位运算符和[]来做一系列的技巧，
which we can talk about later semester,
我们在本学期晚些时候讨论，
to actually now you know, as, as I'm scanning along
现在我进行扫描，
and saying, trying to find, you know, matches on a certain number,
比如试图找到某个数字的匹配，
because these are now 8 bit integers,
因为这些现在是 8 位整数，
I could put them into a single 32 bit integer
我可以把它们放到一个单独的 32 位整数中，
and I'm keeping track of inside my system,
我会在我的系统中跟踪，
oh, it's really at this offset, these different values,
哦，它是在这个偏移量，这些不同的值，
and then now with a single CPU instruction,
现在，使用一条 CPU 指令，
I can operate on four values at once,
我可以一次操作四个值，
what's the problem with this?
这有什么问题？
Yes.
是的。
Okay, excellent, thank you.
好的，太棒了，谢谢。
So his statement is,
所以他的陈述是，
well, what happens, if I have a number that can't be stored in those 8 bits,
如果我有一个数字，不能存储在 8 位中，会发生什么，
that I'm trying to pack them into, right,
我试图将它们打包成的 8 位中，
and so the way you get around this is a technique from Amazon for Redshift,
解决这个问题的方法是来自 Amazon Redshift 的技术，
it's called mostly encoding,
它被称为主要是编码，
where you say,
在那里你可以说，
the, the idea is basically say,
这个想法基本上是说，
most of the data my column is going to be small enough,
我的列中的大多数数据都足够小，
but in the cases where it's not,
但在不够小的情况下，
they they'll keep track of that
他们会跟踪这些数据，
and then store that as a separate in a dictionary, right,
然后将其作为单独的数据存储在字典中，
so again, I have these 32 32 bit numbers,
再次，我有 32 位比特数字，
but I have I have this one 99999999 here,
但是我有这个 99999999 ，
that's really big,
这真的很大，
So I'll store still store them is is eight bits,
所以我仍然会存储它们是 8 位，
but then I'll have a special marker value,
但是我会有一个特殊的标记值，
think like all the bits are set to 1
假设所有位都设置为 1 ，
and then I have a separate table,
然后我有一个单独的表，
that says for a given offset, here's, here's what the original value should be,
表示给定的偏移量，以下是原始值应该是什么，
so now as as I'm scanning along this column,
所以现在，当我沿着这一列扫描时，
if I see my special marker value,
如果我看到我的特殊标记值，
I know that I should look in this offset table
我知道我应该查看这个偏移表，
and find out what the real value should have been.
找出实际值应该是什么。
Yeah, so his statement is,
是的，所以他的说法是，
could you do something with like the triplets,
你能不能对三元组做一些事情，
where instead of just saying everything's always 8 bits,
不是说所有的东西都是 8 位的，
could you say, you know, I have a thousand values that are contiguous,
你能说，我有一千个连续的值，
that you store as 4 bits,
你存储为 4 位，
then I can store them in is 12 bits or whatever.
然后我可以把它们存储在 12 位或其他什么地方。
So that going back to the packs thing,
回到打包的事情，
because they break it up into row groups,
因为它们将其分解为行组，
each row group could have its own compression scheme,
每个行组可以有自己的压缩方案，
so you could do something like that.
所以你可以做这样的事情。
I think Parquet is more,
我认为 Parquet 更加，
Parquet is more aggressive compression than Orc, more complicated,
Parquet 压缩比 Orc 更激进，更复杂，
maybe the other way around,
也许是另一种方式，
one of them, one of them is very simple,
其中的一个非常简单，
one of them does has a bunch of the various tricks you're talking about.
另一个确实有一堆你所说的各种技巧。
All right, so in this example here,
好的，所以在这个例子中，
the original size is 256 bits,
原始大小是 256 位，
but then if I do the mostly encoding,
但如果我进行主要编码，
I used have to store 8x8 bits for the mostly 8 column,
我必须为主要的 8 列存储 8x8 位，
and then assuming that I only need 16 bits for the offset
然后假设我只需要 16 位用于 offset ，
and the 32 bits for the value,
32 位用于 value ，
for this lookup table,
对于这个查找表，
which is not true,
这不是真的，
because obviously allocate more for additional metadata,
因为显然分配更多的用于附加元数据，
but assuming you get it down to that, it's 112 bits,
但假设你得到它，它是 112 位，
so that's pretty good.
所以这是非常好的。
Another trick you do is called bitmap encoding,
你使用的另一个技巧称为位图编码，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
if you have an attribute that has low cardinality,
如果你有一个基数很低的属性，
meaning it has a small number of unique values,
意味着它有少量的唯一值，
where now, instead of storing for every single tuple in, in a column,
现在，不是存储列中的每个 tuple ，
here's the actual value,
而是实际的值，
what I'm staggering to do is maintain bitmaps,
我要做的是维护位图，
where I have one bitmap for every possible value, I could have in the column,
其中我为列中可能具有的每个值都有一个位图，
and the bit is set to 1,
将位设置为 1 ，
based on whether the the column or the attribute, the tuple at that offset has that particular value, right.
基于列或属性，偏移量处的 tuple 是否具有该特定值。
So there are some database systems that,
所以有一些数据库系统，
that provide bitmap indexes that essentially give the same things,
它们提供的位图索引，基本上提供了相同的东西，
you still have the original column,
你仍然保留原来的列，
but then they maintain bitmap indexes,
但它们维护的位图索引，
that will do the same technique that we're seeing here,
将执行与我们在这里看到的相同的技术，
there's a system, there's a company,
有一个系统，有一家公司，
that's gonna come talk about their database system later this semester,
会在本学期晚些时候来谈论他们的数据库，
it's FeatureBase or FeatureForm,
它是 FeatureBase 或 FeatureForm ，
there's two different database have the same name Feature in them,
两个不同的数据库都有 Feature 在名字中，
one of them only stores bitmap indexes,
其中一个只存储位图索引，
they don't, you can't actually store real data, base data.
你不能存储真正的数据库数据。
So the idea is here,
所以，这个想法是，
so say we go back to our isDead column, right,
所以回到我们的 isDead 列，
again, there's only two possible values,
这里只有两种可能的值，
either dead or not dead,
要么死了，要么没死，
instead in storing in the actual single values themselves,
不是存储实际的单个值本身，
I have two bit maps,
我有两个位图，
one says for yes, one says, says no,
一个人说是，一个人说不，
and then there's a bit here, that set in each bitmap,
然后在每个位图中设置一个位，
that corresponds to whether the the original value has that, that bitmap or not,
它对应于原始值是否有那个位图，
it has that particular value or not, right,
它是否有那个特定值，
so I only need now 2 8-bits, 16 bits to store the yes or no,
所以我现在只需要 2 个 8 位， 16 位来存储是或否，
and then now my bitmap is just 18 bits,
然后现在我的位图只有 18 位，
because I have 9 values and I need 2 bits each,
因为我有 9 个值，每个值需要 2 位，
so I can get this down now to 34 bits.
所以我现在可以把它降到 34 位。
What's an obvious problem with this approach?
这种方法最明显的问题是什么？
Yes.
是的。
He said, if your data is high cardinality,
他说，如果你的数据是高基数的，
this is a terrible idea indeed,
这确实是一个糟糕的想法，
yes, it is.
是的，它是。
Let's look at an example,
让我们来看一个例子，
so say we have a customer table like this
假设我们有一个这样的 customer 表，
and we have the zip_code column, right,
我们有一个 zip_code 列，
how many zip codes are in the United States, guess.
美国有多少个邮政编码，猜猜看。
I heard 10000, no, more, 100000, less,
我听到 10000 ，更多， 100000 ，更少，
but now we're doing binary search,
我们在做的是二分查找，
it's 43000, right,
是 43000 ，
assuming we have a table,
假设我们有一个表，
we do 10 million rows
我们有 1000 万行，
and I'm going to build a bitmap for every single unique possible zip code I have,
我将为我拥有的每个唯一的邮政编码构建一个位图，
well, I'm going to need,
好的，我需要，
just to store the data,
只是为了存储数据，
assuming the raw data, assuming we can zip code is 32 bits,
假设原始数据，邮政编码是 32 位，
the raw data is 40 megabytes,
原始数据是 40 兆字节，
but if I had to have a 10 million size bitmap for every single zip code,
但如果我必须为每个邮政编码都有一个 1000 万大小的位图，
now we're at 53G,
现在我们是 53G ，
so clearly, this is a bad idea.
所以很明显，这不是一个好主意。
Furthermore, every time somebody adds a new tuple,
此外，每次有人添加新的 tuple 时，
I have to extend that bitmap,
我都必须扩展该位图，
because I, you know, because it also have to match,
因为它也必须匹配，
I keep adding more, you know, to it,
我一直在添加更多在上面，
so I have to do that for every possible bitmap, right.
所以，我必须为每一种可能的位图这样做。
So bitmpa indexes can make a huge difference,
所以，位图索引可以产生巨大的差异，
but it's really for, like,
但这实际上是为了，
when you have a really small number cardinality like,
当你有一个非常小的基数时，
like less than maybe 10,
比如，可能小于 10 ，
you want to do this,
你想这么做，
and most systems don't do this by default.
大多数系统在默认情况下不会这样做。
All right, delta encoding,
好的，增量编码，
The idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
if the values from one attribute to the next,
如果值从一个属性到下一个，
from one, tuple to the next, sorry,
抱歉，从一个 tuple 到下一个，
if they're close enough to each other,
如果它们彼此足够接近，
maybe, again, I don't need to store the entire value for one tuple,
也许，我不需要存储 tuple 的整个值，
I just need to store the difference of the delta between the previous value.
我只需要存储前一个值之间的差值。
So let's say again, I I have a kind of sensor reading,
假设，我有一种传感器读数，
where I'm keeping track of the temperature in the room,
我在记录房间里的温度，
and every minute I'm, I'm storing the temperature, right,
每一分钟我都在存储温度，
so it is timestamp column here,
所以这里是时间戳列，
assuming that we're storing 64 bits,
假设我们存储的是 64 位，
we know that the time is always going to increment by 1,
我们知道时间总是以 1 递增，
and furthermore, assuming I can keep track of the temperature, you know, in the room or outside
而且，假设我能跟踪室内或室外的温度，
from one minute to the next, there's not going to be dramatic temperature swings, right,
从一分钟到下一分钟，不会有戏剧性的温度波动，
we're not going to go from like 99 degrees to 0 degrees within a minute,
我们不会在一分钟内从华氏 99 度降到 0 度，
and so what I can just do now is
所以我现在能做的就是，
to store, you know, from one tuple to the next,
存储从一个 tuple 到下一个，
what was the difference between the previous one here, right,
与前一次有什么不同，
so in in case of the timestamp,
所以，在时间戳的情况下，
it's just plus one, adding a minute,
它只是加 1 ，加一分钟，
in case of the temperature,
在温度的情况下，
it's some, you know, fractional, decimal difference between the previous one,
它是与前一个的微小分数差异，
I compress this even further now,
我现在进一步压缩它，
because what do I have in this first column here at the timestamp,
因为我在时间戳的第一列中有什么，
what do I have,
我有什么，
a bunch of plus ones,
一大堆加 1 ，
how can we compress that,
我们怎么才能压缩它，
run-length encoding, right.
游程编码，
so we can compress this even further now
所以我们现在可以进一步压缩它，
and convert this into,
并将其转换为，
you know, convert the combination of the delta encoding in run-length encoding
使用游程编码转换增量编码，
to tell you how many plus ones I have afterwards.
来告诉你之后有多少加 1 。
So this is a good example,
所以这是一个很好的例子，
again, we can have this multiplicer effect,
我们可以有乘数效应，
where we can compress the compressed data even further,
我们可以进一步压缩压缩的数据，
because we're putting into a form that that's, that's, that can take advantage of it.
因为我们把它变成了一种可以利用它的形式。
So if you go back to our original data size,
所以，如果回到我们的原始数据大小，
just for the timestamp column itself,
仅就时间戳列本身而言，
we at 320 bits,
我们需要 320 位，
but if we do the delta encoding followed by the RL encoding,
但如果我们先进行增量编码，然后进行游程编码，
we can get it down to 96 bits,
我们可以将其降至 96 位，
again, I'm showing six or seven tuples here,
我在这里展示了六、七个 tuple ，
it's not that big,
它没那么大，
but again, think of it extreme,
但是，把它想象成极端的，
think of like a billion records,
想象一下，大概有 10 亿个记录，
this would be a massive savings.
这将是一笔巨大的节省。
The last one discussed is dictionary compression,
最后讨论的是字典压缩，
because again, I said this is the most common one,
因为我说过，这是最常见的一种，
this is how we're going to get,
这就是我们将如何获得，
this, how most systems are going to express data,
这是大多数系统将如何表达数据，
even for things that aren't strings, right,
即使是对于不是字符串的东西，
in some cases, there are some columnar systems will compress integer data or flow data
在某些情况下，有一些列式系统会将整数数据或流数据压缩，
and putting them to dictionary codes.
将它们放到字典编码中。
The idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
if we have values that we see over and over again,
如果我们有反复看到的值，
instead of storing that value repeatedly within a column,
不是在一列中重复存储该值，
we're going to convert that into some 32 bit integer,
我们将把它转换为一些 32 位整数，
and then we maintain a mapping data structure, the dictionary,
然后我们维护一个映射数据结构，即字典，
that knows how to take that, that dictionary code, the 32 bit integer,
它知道如何获取它的字典编码，32 位整数，
and convert it back into an original value,
并将其转换回原始值，
typically we're going to have, it's a one to one correspondence,
通常我们会有一对一的对应，
for one value, we'll have one dictionary code,
对于一个值，我们将有一个字典编码，
there is some techniques,
这里有一些技巧，
I don't think any commercial system does this,
我认为任何商业系统都不会这样做，
where you can say, if I see multiple attributes, the patterns together,
你可以说，如果我看到多个属性，模式在一起，
I'll convert the combination of the two of them or three of them into a single dictionary code
我会将它们两个或三个的组合转换为单个字典代码，
to get even further compression,
以获得进一步的压缩，
but again, I've only seen that in academic literature.
但是，我只在学术文献中看到过这个。
And then we need a way to do fast encoding and decoding on the fly,
然后，我们需要一种快速编码和解码的方法，
that allows to do both range and point queries,
允许同时进行范围和点查询，
so point queries are obvious,
所以点查询是显而易见的，
like I want to be able to say,
就像我想要说的那样，
you know, the string Andy maps to, you know, code 101,
字符串 Andy 映射到的编码 101 ，
I know how to do the exact lookup at those,
我知道如何做精确的查找，
but ideally I want to be able to also be able to do range queries on compressed data,
但理想情况下，我希望能够对压缩数据进行范围查询，
and so I want my dictionary codes to have the same ordering that the original values actually did, too,
所以，我希望我的字典编码也具有与原始值相同的顺序，
and we'll see how to do that in a second.
我们稍后会看看如何做到这个。
So say this is my original data,
假设这是我的原始数据，
a bunch of names of my former students,
一堆我以前学生的名字，
then the compressed version of this could be,
然后，它的压缩版本可以是，
again, I have my original column, convert those into 32 bit integers,
我有我的原始列，把它们转换成 32 位整数，
and then I just had this mapping table here,
然后我就有了这个映射表，
that converts the, allows me to look up,
转换，允许我查找，
to say, for given code, what's the original value
对于给定的编码，原始值是什么，
or for a given original value, what's what's the code,
或者给定的原始值，代码是什么，
and that's the dictionary.
这就是字典。
So now we can go back to my example,
所以现在我们可以回到我的例子，
that I had in the very beginning with me and DJ 2PL,
我在最开始的例子，有我和 DJ 2PL ，
where SELECT * FROM users WHERE name equals Andy,
SELECT * FROM user WHERE name = "Andy" ，
I can convert the string Andy into the dictionary code
我可以把字符串 Andy 转换成字典编码，
by doing a lookup first in the dictionary,
通过首先在字典中进行查找，
then now I scan through my, my column
然后，现在我浏览我的列，
and just do lookup or do do comparisons based on the integers,
只进行查找或基于整数进行比较，
so I don't need to go through as I'm scanning along,
所以我不需要在扫描的时候通过，
if I don't do, if I don't compress my, my constant,
如果我不压缩我的常量，
then as I scan along,
那么当我扫描的时候，
I gotta go decompress each of these one by one
我必须一个一个地解压缩，
and then do my lookup,
然后再进行查找，
I'm basically losing all the benefit of compression, right,
我基本上失去了所有压缩的好处，
and that's what MySQL has to do,
这就是 MySQL 必须做的，
because they can't interpret what's actually in the dictionary,
因为它们无法解释词典中的实际内容，
they can't interpret what the compressed bytes actually mean,
它们无法解释压缩字节的实际含义，
but in this case here,
但在这里，
because we're the database system,
因为我们是数据库系统，
we, we built the dictionary, we control it,
我们建立了字典，我们控制它，
we know how to read it and interpret it,
我们知道如何阅读和解释它，
we can and I mean in SQL, so we know what the query wants to do,
我们可以，我的意思是，在 SQL 中，我们知道查询想要做什么，
we know how to take that constant,
我们知道如何获取该常量，
convert it to the dictionary code,
将其转换为字典代码，
then then do our scan directly on the compressed data.
然后直接对压缩数据进行扫描。
So, how do we actually do this,
所以，我们到底要怎么做，
do the encoding and decoding, right,
做编码和解码，
well, again, for a given, given uncompressed value,
对于一个给定的未压缩的值，
we know had a way to go compressed form and then reverse it,
我们知道有一种方法到压缩形式，然后反转它，
so the key thing you point out is,
所以你要指出的关键是，
there's not going to be a magic hash function that can do this for us, right,
不会有一个神奇的散列函数可以为我们做到这个，
any reversible hash function is, is going to
任何可逆的散列函数都会，
generate something that's something much larger likely than the original of value,
产生比原始值大得多的东西，
so not get it down to a 32 bit integer, right,
所以不会把它缩小到 32 位整数，
so we're going to have to build a data structure,
所以，我们必须建立一个数据结构，
that we maintain that allows us to do this.
我们维护，使我们能够做到这个。
And as I said,
就像我说的，
we want something that's going to be preserve the ordering of the original values,
我们想要的是保持原始值的顺序，
such that the compressed data, the compressed dictionary codes,
这样压缩数据，压缩的字典代码，
those things have the same ordering leographically or as the original data does.
这些东西在词法上或与原始数据具有相同的顺序。
So going back here, right,
所以回到这里，
if I have again, I have a bunch of these names,
我有一堆名字，
I want my, I want the dictionary that I'm generating to the codes have such that,
我想要我生成的字典到代码有，
if one, if the original value comes before in the, in the, in the ordering, before another original value,
如果一个原始值在另一个原始值的顺序之前，
is dictionary code should come before it as well,
字典编码也应该在它之前，
so I would have my dictionary is basically sorted,
所以我会让我的字典是排序的，
so now this allows me to do queries like this,
现在，这允许我执行这样的查询，
SELECT * FROM users WHREE name LIKE Andy,
SELECT * FROM users WHERE name LIKE "And%" ，
And, followed by the wildcard,
And ，后面跟着通配符，
and so if we operate directly on compressed data,
所以，如果我们直接对压缩数据进行操作，
we can convert this LIKE clause into a BETWEEN clause,
我们可以将这个 LIKE 子句转换为 BETWEEN 子句，
because we could look up in the dictionary,
因为我们可以在字典中查找，
run the LIKE portion, just on the dictionary, the values,
运行 LIKE 部分，在字典值上，
find the ones that match, find the min and max values for the matching values,
找到匹配的，找到匹配值的最小值和最大值，
and then rewrite the LIKE into a BETWEEN calls,
然后将 LIKE 重写为 BETWEEN 调用，
and then now run through my column while it's still compressed.
然后在我的列还在压缩的时候，运行它。
Again, we can do this,
我们可以这样做，
because it's, it's SQL,
因为它是 SQL ，
we know, we know it's in the WHERE clause,
我们知道在 WHERE 子句中，
it's not arbitrary Python code or C code,
它不是任意的 Python 代码或 C 代码，
we know exactly what the, what the WHERE clause wants to do
我们确切地知道 WHERE 子句想要做什么，
and we can be smart, intelligent and convert this,
我们可以聪明地转换这个，
do the rewriting for us.
为我们做重写。
And again, you as the, the, the application programmer
你们作为应用程序程序员，
or not you guys, but some Javascript programmer,
或者不是你们，是一些 Javascript 程序员，
they don't have to know what the hell going underneath the covers, right,
他们不需要知道下面到底发生了什么，
they just write the LIKE clause
他们只需编写 LIKE 子句，
and the database system can be can be smart and rewrite it for you
数据库系统就可以变得智能，并为你重写它，
and get better performance.
从而获得更好的性能。
So, in some cases here,
所以，在这里的某些情况下，
you still have to do,
你仍然必须做，
the question is,
问题是，
whether you still to perform original column,
你是否仍然执行原始列，
in this case here,
在这种情况下，
since I need the, I need the output of of the, of the name attribute,
因为我需要 name 属性的输出，
I still have to go rip through the column
我仍然要去[撕开]列，
and actually look at them,
真正地查看它们，
in some cases, though, the database system can be even smarter
在某些情况下，数据库系统甚至可以更智能，
and it can answer queries without actually looking at the compressed data,
它可以在查看压缩数据的情况下回答查询，
but just operate directly on the dictionary.
而是直接在字典上操作。
So instead of saying SELECT name FROM users,
所以，如果不是 SELECT name FROM users ，
if it was DISTINCT name FROM users,
而是 DISTINCT name FROM users ，
where I don't need to get the actual tuples themselves,
我不需要获得实际的 tuple 本身，
I just need to get the actual values that are unique,
我只需要获得唯一的实际值，
then for this query here,
然后，对于这里的查询，
after I do my conversion to, converting to BETWEEN,
在转换为 BETWEEN 之后，
or convert the this wildcard here into the the dictionary values,
或者将这里的通配符转换为字典值之后，
I only need to know what what values actually exist in the dictionary,
我只需要知道字典中实际存在什么值，
and I don't need to go look at the actual column,
我不需要查看实际列，
for this query here with a DISTINCT,
对于使用 DISTINCT 的查询，
you know, assuming I only have four names in my table,
假设我的表中只有四个名字，
but I have a billion rows,
但我有十亿行，
I only need to look at four rows in the dictionary to answer it,
我只需要查看字典中的四行就可以回答它，
and again, I've said this multiple times,
再次，我已经说过很多次了，
we can do this,
我们可以这样做，
because the data, because the database is responsible for compressing this,
因为数据库负责压缩这个，
now, Parquet and, or one of the big limitations that they have is,
现在， Parquet 或者说，他们有一个很大的限制是，
they don't actually expose the dictionary to you,
他们不会向你公开字典，
when you use their libraries and utilities,
当你使用他们的库和程序时，
so you can't do this trick I'm talking about here,
所以你不能做我在这里说的这个技巧，
if you're using Parquet or Orc, right,
如果你使用 Parquet 或 Orc ，
Parquet, and Orc decompress the data,
Parquet 和 Orc 解压缩数据，
when it gives, it back to you,
当它把数据还给你时，
you can't operate directly on compressed data,
你不能直接对压缩数据进行操作，
that's actually one of the biggest limitations of, in my opinion, of those two formats,
在我看来，这是这两种格式最大的限制之一，
but again, other systems that do native compression without Parquet, Orc can, can, can do this trick.
但是，其他不使用 Parquet Orc ，执行简单压缩的系统可以做这个技巧。
All right, so what is this data structure,
好的，那么这个数据结构是什么，
what is the data structure we're going to use for our dictionary,
我们的字典将使用什么数据结构，
so the most common approach is going to be a really simple array,
最常见的方法将是非常简单的数组，
and this works great, if the files are mutable,
如果文件是不变的，这很有效，
because I build the array once
因为我只构建一次数组，
and I never to resize things,
并且我永远不会调整某些东西的大小，
insert things in place
原地插入某些东西，
and to move things around,
也不会移动东西，
I can just build it once I'm done,
我只需在完成后就可以构建它，
if you need something that's dynamic and can support updates,
如果你需要一些动态的，并且可以支持更新的东西，
you need either a hash table or a B+ tree,
你需要一个哈希表或者一个 B+ 树，
these are, the hash table is I think less common there,
这些是，哈希表，我想不那么常见，
actually, these things are less common,
事实上，这些东西不太常见，
most people do the array
大多数人做数组，
and assume the blocks are going be, the compressed blocks are going to be immutable
并假设压缩的块将是不可变的，
and only if I need to to rebuild it,
并且只有当我需要重建它的时候，
then I'll rebuild the array.
然后我会重建数组。
I realize I'm over time,
我注意到我超时了，
let me show roughly what it looks like,
让我粗略地展示一下它的样子，
so basically you have your original data in your column,
所以，基本上你的列中有原始数据，
so the first thing you need to do is build your dictionary
所以你需要做的第一件事就是建立你的字典，
and again, all that's going to be is a sorted list of the of the values you have
然后，所有要做的就是你拥有的值的排序列表，
and then the, and you store the length of the, of the string
然后，你存储字符串的长度，
and then now the dictionary code is going to be, is just an offset into this array here,
然后，字典代码就是这个数组的偏移量，
so my compressed data would look like this,
所以我的压缩数据是这样的，
and these are just offsets, the byte offset into the array,
这些只是数组中的字节偏移量，
and so now when I'm doing a scan
所以现在当我做扫描时，
and I want to say, okay, if I have the second one, second entry, it's 17,
我想说，如果我有第二个条目，它是 17 ，
I jump a by offset at 17
我跳跃到 17 的偏移量，
and I can look in the,
我可以在里面查看，
down here,
在这里，
I can look in the header and tell me how big is the string afterwards.
我可以查看 header ，然后知道后面的字符串有多大。
So the dictionary itself is literally just an array packed of bytes like that.
所以，字典本身就是一个由这样的字节组成的数组。
Okay?
好的？
All right, so to finish up,
好的，最后，
you know this row store versus column store to be really important
这个行存储、列存储非常重要，
and we'll see this show up when we talk about query execution and other things,
我们会在讨论查询执行和其他事情时看到这个，
mostly before before the midterm,
大多数在期中之前，
because again the, the distinction or the difference between a row store and a column store system
因为行存储和列存储系统之间的区别
have ramifications through throughout all other parts of the database system,
影响到数据库系统的所有其他部分，
how you do recovery,
如何进行恢复，
how you could do query execution,
如何进行查询执行，
how you want to run transactions,
如何运行事务，
how you want to optimize your queries,
如何优化查询，
and so it's really important to understand this now
所以现在理解这一点非常重要，
and we'll, we'll, we'll see the tradeoffs between the two approaches
我们将看到这两种方法之间的权衡，
again and again throughout the entire semester.
在整个学期中一次又一次地看到。
And then most data systems to get the best compression ratio,
然后大多数数据系统要获得最佳的压缩比，
you want to do it natively to yourself
你想要对自己进行简单压缩，
and dictionary coding is common one.
而字典编码是常见的一种。
So, I showed this three, three lectures ago,
我在过去三节课中展示了这个，
there was two problems in database storage,
在数据库存储中存在两个问题，
first, how we can represent data on disk,
首先，我们如何在磁盘上表示数据，
we've covered that so far,
到目前为止，我们已经介绍了这个，
so starting next week,
所以，从下周开始，
now when we bring things into memory,
当我们将事物带入内存时，
what do we do with it,
我们将如何处理它，
how do we store it,
我们如何存储它，
and how do we write things back out safely,
如何安全地写回内容，
when we make changes.
当我们进行更改时。
Alright, hit it.
好的，开始。